women tend to be more Unhappily Married
女性的婚姻不幸率往往高于
than men and 80% of the time women bring
男性，而且80%的情况下，女性会主动
up problems in a relationship but 69% of
提出感情中的问题，但其中69%的
all problems are not solvable so if you
问题都无法解决。因此，如果你把
rely on problems getting solved as an
问题解决率作为衡量
relationship it's not going to look good
感情成功与否的标准，那可就太不靠谱了。Jong
Dr Jong and Dr Julie gotman
博士和Julie Gotman博士是
world-renowned researchers and clinical
世界知名的研究员和临床
psychologists who've been married 36
心理学家，他们结婚36
years and have spent the last 50 years
年，并在过去的50年里一直致力于
studying love you made something called
研究爱情。你们创建了一个名为“
love lab what is that we followed 3,000
爱情实验室”的项目，追踪了3000对
couples it taught us the difference
夫妇，从中我们了解到
between what masters of relationship do
成功伴侣
and what disasters do what advice would
和失败伴侣之间的区别。
you give to me then cuddle 96% of non-
你们会给我什么建议呢？拥抱。96%不
cuddlers had an awful sex life anything
爱拥抱的人性生活很糟糕。还有其他建议吗？是的，现在
else yes the hookup culture is thriving
约会文化盛行，这是
is that a problem yes why okay so let me
个问题吗？是的，为什么呢？好的，让我
point out something that everybody needs
指出一点，这一点每个人都需要
to hear so and also kissing is very
听到。还有，接吻的力量非常
powerful men who kiss their wives
强大。在工作前亲吻妻子的男性
four years longer than men who don't in
比不这样做的男性寿命长四年。
your research you found that during
你们的研究发现，在
conflict couples who show four key
冲突中，那些展现出以下四个关键特征的伴侣，寿命更长：
behaviors mean that an argument is
这些行为意味着争吵注定
doomed yes and they are criticism
失败，是的，它们包括批评和
defensiveness the third one was the
防御。第三个是
worst and that was that was the best
最糟糕的，也是
predictor of relationship breakup and
预测关系破裂的最佳指标。
the fourth
第四个
was John Julie can you role play the
是约翰和朱莉，你们能角色扮演一下
behavior that a couple who are destined
注定
to fail would exhibit oh yes
失败的情侣会表现出的行为吗？哦，好的。
many of you have decided to watch our
你们这么多人决定观看我们的
show um and so many of you have decided
节目，这对我来说简直太疯狂了，而且你们这么多人决定
to subscribe to our show we now have
订阅我们的节目。我们现在
five million subscribers on YouTube
在YouTube上有500万订阅者，
which is a number that I just can't
这个数字我简直无法想象，这绝对是
comprehend and it's a dream that I
我做梦都想不到的。
absolutely never could have had we
我们
started the dire of a CO just over three
三年多前开始制作《Dire of a CO》，
years ago now and in my wildest
我最乐观的
expectations we might have had 100,000
预期是现在可能有10万
subscribers by now so you can imagine
订阅者。所以你们可以想象
how shocked I am that so many of you
我有多么震惊，你们这么多人
have chosen to tune into these
选择
conversations every week um and spend
每周收看我们的节目，花
some time with us so thank you and I
时间和我们在一起。谢谢你们。
made a deal with you I made a deal that
我和你们做了个约定，
if you subscribe to this show that we
如果你们订阅这个节目，我们
would continue to raise the bar and in
会不断提高标准，到
2024 we're going to raise the bar like
2024年，我们将提高…… 酒吧将以前所未有的方式呈现！
last 9 months on a surprise for all of
过去九个月，我一直在为所有订阅节目的朋友们准备一个惊喜，
I'm very excited to deliver that for you
我非常激动地要把它带给大家。节目的
the production's going to change we're
制作方式将会改变，我们会
going to go even further with our guests
与嘉宾进行更深入的交流，
and we're going to tell even more Global
讲述更多全球性的
stories so as always if you appreciate
故事。所以，和以往一样，如果您喜欢
what we doing here the simple free favor
我们的节目，
I'll ask from you is to hit the
我唯一的小小请求就是点击
Subscribe button let's get on with the
订阅按钮。让我们开始今天的
[Music]
[音乐]
episode John Julie you've both been
节目吧。约翰和朱莉，你们两位
studying the subject of love for more
研究爱情已经
than 50
超过50
years you've written books you've done a
年了，你们写过书，做过
lot of primary research you run
大量的实地研究，你们还运营着
something called The Love lab I'm going
一个名为“爱情实验室”的项目。我先问
to start with you Julie
你，朱莉·
M what is the mission
M，你们的使命是什么？
that you're on and why love that is the
为什么是爱情？这是
most wonderful question in the universe
宇宙中最美妙的问题。
here's why we have a world as we all
我们都
know that is full of conflict is full of
知道，这个世界充满了冲突、
uh antipathy is full of violence
敌意、暴力、
domestic
家庭
violence all kinds of clashes between
暴力以及人与人之间各种各样的冲突。
people and we wanted to focus on love
我们想聚焦于爱情，
because love is the great healer right
因为爱情是伟大的疗愈力量，
it heals people's hearts it heals
它能治愈人们的心灵。 它能治愈
people's Souls it brings people together
人们的灵魂，它能将人们凝聚在一起，
it unifies people but nobody has taken
它能使人们团结一致，但没有人
successful couples did to really
真正学习过人际关系的基础知识，没有人知道如何建立平静、温柔、充满同情心的、富有成效的关系。在研究之初，我们对成功的伴侣如何
solidify their relationship and sustain
巩固和维系关系一无所知。
it so John and his wonderful colleague
因此，约翰和他出色的同事
Robert levenson did some of that
罗伯特·莱文森进行了一些
earliest research that taught us the
早期研究，这些研究让我们了解了
relationship do and what disasters do so
人际关系大师的做法和人际关系灾难者的做法之间的区别，以便
we could help as many people as possible
我们能够帮助尽可能多的人。
and John the same question for you with
约翰，同样的问题也想问你，在
all the work that you've done in your
你一生所做的所有工作中，
life life what is it that you're seeking
你想要为那些阅读你作品的
to deliver to the person that consumes
人提供什么？
that work what is it you're seeking to
你想要
do for them well Bob and I started
为他们做些什么？鲍勃和我之所以开始
studying relationships because we were
研究人际关系，是因为我们在
so incompetent at it and we we're just
这方面太无能了，我们简直是两个
too clueless guys going from one
一窍不通的人，不断地经历着一段又一段糟糕的
relationship disaster to another and we
感情。我们
were really curious about whether there
真的很好奇是否
were people out there who could do it
有人能够处理
well and we found they were and you know
好人际关系，我们发现确实有。
and then we thought how are they
然后我们思考，他们和我们这些经历过一段又一段糟糕感情的
different from people you know who like
人有什么不同？
another and we had no idea we really had
我们当时对此一无所知。
very few hypotheses when we started so
我们一开始其实只有很少的假设，纯粹
it was just curiosity uh and we weren't
是出于好奇。我们根本
interested in helping anybody at all we
没想过要帮助任何人，只是
were just curious about finding out what
想弄清楚其中的
the differences were and then 26 years
差异。26年前，
ago Julia and I decided to work together
我和朱莉娅决定一起工作。她是
and she's a clinical psychologist she
一位临床心理学家，她
wants to help people and and I thought
想帮助别人。我当时觉得
it was impossible to change
改变
relationships because if you can predict
人际关系是不可能的，因为如果你能
with such high accuracy that a
如此准确地预测一段
relationship is doomed or it works how
关系的成败，
can you change it you know it seemed
你怎么可能改变它呢？这听起来似乎
seemed impossible but Julie's really an
不可能。但朱莉娅是个
optimist and really cares about people
乐观主义者，她真的很关心别人。
and so we got together and we thought
所以我们走到了一起，心想
well we need a theory if we're going to
如果我们想帮助别人，就需要一个理论，
help people cuz every relationship is
因为每段关系都不
different and so first we built a theory
一样。所以我们先建立了一个理论，
and then we tested it so that's how I
然后进行了验证。这就是我
got into it really I didn't have a
进入这个领域的契机，我其实并没有什么特定的
mission so how did you both come to
目标。那么，你们俩是怎么开始
study and work together on the subject
研究爱情这个主题的呢？
particular well John had already been
约翰当时已经在
studying it right right so uh we met
研究这个主题了，对吧？我们
what almost 38 years ago and what
大约在38年前相遇。当时的情况
happened is that I'd be coming home
是，我回家后会在
dinner John would come home from the lab
晚餐时谈论我的临床案例，而约翰则会从实验室回来……
findings he had that were really
他分享了一些统计数据和研究结果，这些都非常令人
thrilling and after a while um he was he
兴奋。过了一段时间，他
was garnering such incredible
积累了大量令人难以置信的
information such great knowledge that
信息和知识。有
one day we were out in the middle of the
一天，我们划着
canoeing and I said honey let's take
独木舟在海上，我说：“亲爱的，我们把
this stuff out of the Ivory Tower let's
这些东西从象牙塔里拿出来吧，让我们
based on what these successful couples
根据这些成功伴侣维系
love it's such a beautiful thing we see
爱情的方式，建立一套理论和干预措施。我们看到的真是一件美好的事情。”
and he said sure why not and we did and
他说：“当然可以，为什么不呢？” 于是我们就这么做了。
joh what was that research well you know
约翰，那项研究是什么呢？你知道，
Bob and I found that there really were
鲍勃和我发现，确实存在一些
masters of relationships and we spent a
维系关系的高手。我们花了
Dozen Years studying gay and lesbian
十二年时间研究同性恋
couples too same thing there there were
伴侣，结果也一样。有些
people who knew how to have
人懂得如何经营
relationships and they were very
关系，他们与
different from the couples who are
那些
struggling and most of the clinical
苦苦挣扎的伴侣截然不同。大多数临床
books have been written by therapist IST
书籍都是由治疗师撰写的，他们
who never saw the good relationships and
从未见过美好的关系。
so we had information that was very new
所以我们掌握了一些非常新颖
and it was pretty fascinating um but the
且引人入胜的信息。但是
question was could we actually turn a
问题是，我们真的能把一场
disaster into a master could we prevent
灾难变成一场胜利吗？我们能预防
relationship disaster we didn't know so
关系灾难吗？我们不知道。所以，这其实是一个
it was kind of a question you know was
问题，你知道，
it just correlation or were the findings
这仅仅是相关性吗？ 这些发现是否
causal and so it was really uh curiosity
具有因果关系？所以，这真的只是出于好奇心。
papers have you published now uh couple
你们现在发表了多少篇研究论文？
hundred I think and how many books
我想大概几百篇吧。
between you have you written Julie I
你们俩一共写了多少本书？朱莉，我
think we're on 52 maybe how many couples
想大概有52本吧。
have you studied John well a latest
你们研究过多少对夫妇？约翰，最近的一项
study involved over 40,000 couples
研究涉及超过4万对夫妇，研究人员
looking at their questionnaires and
查看了他们的问卷，这些
couples about to start therapy but
夫妇即将开始接受治疗。但研究人员
following couples in the lab that the
在实验室里跟踪研究了这些夫妇，那个
kind of lab that Bob levenson and I
实验室是我和鲍勃·莱文森共同
created
创建的。大约有
uh about 3,000 couples and Bob studied a
3000对夫妇，鲍勃对一
group of couples for 20 years the same
组夫妇进行了20年的研究，这
for 20 years so the group of couples in
组夫妇在研究开始时分别处于40多岁和60多岁。他实际上获得了20年的资助，所以
the 40s were now in their 60s and you
40多岁的夫妇现在已经60多岁了，你
can compare them to the couples 20 years
可以将他们与20年前60多岁的夫妇进行比较。最终，这是
being you know a 40-year longitudinal
一项长达40年的纵向
study has anyone ever studied couples
研究。有人研究过夫妇
for that l length of time no not really
这么长时间吗？没有，真的没有。
it really was a first when people think
当人们思考
love I don't think they necessarily hold
爱情这个话题时，我并不认为他们一定把它看得
it in such high importance in their life
那么重要，
they think about other thing especially
他们更关注其他事情，尤其是在爱情与
as it correlates to our health outcomes
健康结果相关的情况下。
so like you know my physical health
比如，你知道，人们认为
deprioritizing love as a path to having
爱情对
good physical health or does our love
身体健康的重要性低于其他途径，这种想法是否正确？或者说，我们的爱情
and relationships correlate to our our
和人际关系是否真的与我们的
physical health our chance of disease
身体健康、患病几率等因素相关？在
field that started kind of when I
我
started doing my research and it's
开始研究的时候，出现了一个新的领域，
called social epidemiology a guy named
叫做社会流行病学。一位名叫伦纳德·
Leonard Sim started at Berkeley with his
西姆（Leonard Sim）的学者和他的
student Lisa burkeman and they did this
学生丽莎·伯克曼（Lisa Burkeman）在伯克利大学开展了一项
uh study called the Alam County study
名为“阿拉姆县研究”的研究，
where they studied 9,000 people and S
他们调查了9000人。西姆
was interested in diet he was interested
对饮食和
in cholesterol and he found that Chinese
胆固醇很感兴趣，他发现华裔
American immigrants just lived a lot
美国移民的寿命
longer and were a lot healthier than
更长，健康状况也更好，甚至比
Americans were even Chinese American
美国人，包括华裔美国
immigrants so he was kind of curious
移民本身的寿命都更长。所以他很好奇，
about you know what really was the
究竟是什么造成了这种
difference was it the diet was it and he
差异？是饮食吗？他
found it was really Community it was
发现真正的原因是社区，是
really that these people moved with
这些人与
their friends and he found in general
朋友一起生活。他发现，总的来说，
that the quality of people's closest
人们最亲密
relationships really predicted longevity
关系的质量…… 预测寿命的
very strong prediction too so it's
预测非常有力，因此它
become a whole field called social
发展成了一个名为社会流行病学的全新领域。
epidemology and people have studied the
人们研究
immune system and you know found that
免疫系统，发现
all over the planet people who are
全球范围内，
socially isolated who have bad
社交孤立、人际关系差的人寿命更短，更容易生病，
get sick and die a lot younger and that
寿命也更短；而
people have great relationships they
人际关系良好的人寿命
live a lot longer and the quality of
更长，生活质量更高，
happier and so it seems to make a real
也更快乐。这似乎会产生巨大的
big difference modern social psychology
影响。现代社会心理学也
has been finding the same thing with
发现，
people's relationship to
人们与
strangers that that affects health so if
陌生人的关系会影响健康，这一点与此类似。如果
you reach out to strangers and in in the
你主动与陌生人交流，比如
morning if you're commuting having a
早上通勤时
conversation with the commuter next to
与旁边的人聊天，
you then you're open to learning about
了解
their lives that also affects your
他们的生活，这也会影响你的
Health and
健康和
Longevity so we're really a very social
寿命。我们人类确实是一个非常社会化的
species it's interesting because we
物种。有趣的是，我们
spend a lot of time you know going to
花很多时间去
the gym or thinking about our diet or
健身房，或者思考饮食
something but what you were saying and I
等等，但正如你所说，我
think what a lot of your work has
认为你的许多研究都
uncovered is that we should be investing
揭示了这一点：我们应该以
in the same way in relationships in a
同样的方式，有
really intentional way and especially
意识地投入到人际关系中，尤其是在
when we consider the nature of the world
考虑到自然规律的情况下。
now where we're getting lonier and more
如今这个世界，我们比以往任何时候都更加孤独和
detached than ever before no one taught
疏离。我这辈子从来没有人教过
me at any point in my life to think of
我把
my relationships like the gym yeah right
人际关系比作健身房。是啊，
what's your take on that Julie well uh
朱莉，你对此有什么看法？嗯，我
myself I love going to the gym but um
自己也是个健身爱好者，我喜欢去健身房。但
one thing that I'm really remembering is
我真正记住的一件事是，
that uh people people whose parents
父母离异的人，平均寿命比在
with an intact family people who grew up
完整家庭中长大的人短四年；那些在离异家庭中长大，最终自己也离婚的人，平均寿命比在完整家庭中长大的人
divorcing lived eight years less so you
短八年。所以你
can see how important love is and we're
可以看出爱情有多么重要。我们
beginning to understand all of this by
开始通过
looking at things like
研究
oxytocin
催产素、
serotonin versus things like adrenaline
血清素等激素，以及肾上腺素
and cortisol which are stress
和皮质醇等压力
hormones that will flood the body and
激素来理解这一切。压力激素会在
stress the body when we're in a bad
我们处于糟糕的关系中时涌入体内，给身体带来压力。
relationship you made something called
你创建了一个叫做“
The Love
爱情
lab very curious name place I think I'd
实验室”的地方，名字真奇怪，我想去
like to go um what is the love lab
看看。嗯，“爱情实验室”是什么？嗯，这是
well it got named that by the BBC when
BBC在
they did a a show on our newlywed study
制作我们新婚夫妇研究节目时起的名字。
but it was it was basically an apartment
基本上，我们把拍摄地点
like setting and couple spent 24 hours
设在一个类似公寓的房间里，一对夫妇在那里待了24小时，
there and the cameras were rolling the
摄像机在
whole time they were awake and and like
他们醒着的这段时间里全程拍摄。
Bob and I did we synchronized
我和鲍勃把
physiological data to the video time
生理数据与视频时间
code so we could you know see what was
码同步，这样我们就能看到
what they were doing what they were
他们在做什么，他们在
saying to one another and at the same
说什么，同时
time be able to look at their heart
还能观察他们的
rates and their blood velocity and
心率、血流速度
things like that and and we measured
等等。我们还测量了
other physiological things and immune
其他生理指标和免疫
variables as well so that was basically
变量。这基本上就是我们的
the lab and we followed couples a couple
实验室。我们在
of months after the wedding many of them
婚礼后的几个月里跟踪拍摄了这些夫妇，其中很多夫妇后来
uh as they got pregnant and had babies I
怀孕生子了。我从
interaction from some of my friends who
一些
were experts in that field and we
在该领域有专长的朋友那里学习了如何研究亲子互动，我们也
followed the children as they got older
跟踪拍摄了孩子们长大后的情况。这就像一个
so that was kind of the lab it was just
实验室，目的是
to see whether uh there was any
看看
predictability in relationships if we
如果我们
weren't telling people what to talk
不告诉人们该说什么，
about just watching them as they might
只是观察他们如何
normally go about a typical day so let
度过平常的一天，他们的关系是否存在任何可预测性。所以让
me get this straight you you have these
我解释一下，这些
people come to this sort of normal
人来到一个看似普通的
setting kind of like an apartment but
公寓式环境中，但
it's really a laboratory where they're
实际上这是一个实验室，他们在这里接受
being studied for their physiological
生理生物
biomarkers of I don't know heart rate
标志物的研究。 我不知道心率之类的
things like that you just watch them
东西，你只需要观察他们，
well they're being videotaped right and
他们会被录像，对吧？
that video tape then afterwards is
然后这些录像会被精确到百分之一秒地
analyzed hundredth of a second by
分析，
hundredth of a second corresponding also
同时还会结合
to their physiological
他们的生理
measures and we're analyzing all of that
指标进行分析。我们会分析所有
tape in terms of the content of what
录像的内容，包括
they're saying what their body movements
他们说的话、他们的肢体动作、
are what their facial expressions are
他们的面部表情、
what emotions are they expressing how
他们表达的情绪、他们是如何
are they expressing those emotions if
表达这些情绪的，以及
any are they responding to each other's
他们是否对彼此的亲密
bids for connection we looked at so much
举动做出了回应。我们查看了大量的
data and it was a gold mine it taught us
数据，这简直是个金矿！它教会了我们
so much not only about the best way for
很多东西，不仅包括
couples to manage conflict but even more
情侣处理冲突的最佳方法，更
important how do couples create a deeper
重要的是，它教会了我们情侣如何建立更深厚的
friendship with one another and by then
友谊。那时
we'd already known that friendship in a
我们已经知道，在一段
relation ship also helps create more
关系中，友谊有助于在长久的感情中创造更多的
passion and good sex in a longlasting
激情和美好的性生活。
relationship so there was so much for us
所以我们有很多东西要
to learn it was exciting going into that
学，
study at the love lab what were the sort
在爱情实验室进行这项研究令人兴奋。
afterwards that are misconceptions about
之后你发现了哪些关于
relationships so you know I can think of
恋爱关系的重大误解？我知道我可以马上想到
a couple off the top of my head but
几个，但
you'll know them better what are the big
你可能更了解它们。那么，主要的
misconceptions that you discovered from
误解是什么呢？ 朱莉，你从
that start with you Julie a lot of
你的研究开始就发现，很多
people think that sustaining a good
人认为维持一段良好的
relationship takes huge effort you know
关系需要付出巨大的努力，比如
takes really figuring out things like
真正理解一些事情，像
active listening where if you say to me
积极倾听。如果你对我说：“
Stephen you know I am really angry
斯蒂芬，你知道吗，我真的很生气，
because you keep leaving the lid off the
因为你总是忘记盖
toothpaste what's the matter with you
牙膏盖。你怎么了？
and how do I respond to that well we
我该如何回应？”我们
would learn that criticism for example
会发现，批评，比如“
you always you never those are
你总是……你从来不……”，这些
criticisms didn't work to manage
批评并不能解决
conflict on the other hand what we also
冲突。另一方面，我们也
saw is that when somebody made a little
看到，当有人做出一些
tiny bid for connection for example
小小的举动来建立联系时，比如，
there was a big window in this apartment
公寓里有一扇大窗户，你
looking out the window and saying oh my
看着窗外说：“天哪，
God there's a beautiful bird in the tree
树上有一只漂亮的鸟儿！”
what does your partner do this proved to
你的伴侣会怎么做？事实证明，这非常
be incred ibly important does your
重要。你的
partner either turn against you by
伴侣会反驳你
saying stop interrupting me I'm trying
说：“别打断我，我在
to read or ignore you completely which
看书！”还是完全无视你，保持
is silence not paying attention or look
沉默，不去注意你？或者
out the window too and say huh
也看着窗外说：“嗯，真漂亮！”？就这么简单，就能为
better friendship for a couple and we
情侣建立更好的友谊。我们
found that the couples who were
发现，那些最终走到一起的情侣，
85% of the time the couples who ended up
85%的人会关注彼此的这些小细节来建立联系。 那些最终
splitting up unhappy divorced
不幸福地分手的夫妻中，有
33% of the time so listen to that
33%最终离婚。所以，听听这其中的
difference just between saying uhhuh and
区别，仅仅是“嗯嗯”和什么
saying nothing let's start there then I
也不说之间的区别。我们就从这里开始吧。
am I think I am guilty of being very
我觉得我在这方面做得非常糟糕，我很难积极
very bad at responding positively to
回应
bids for connection from my partner this
伴侣想要建立联系的请求。这
is actually one of the central issues
实际上是
that we've struggled with over the last
我们过去
couple of months is my partner will come
几个月一直在努力解决的核心问题之一。我的伴侣像
home like usually I'm coming home she's
往常一样回家，她比
already home just before me and I'm
我先到家，而我仍然沉浸在工作中，
I'm thinking about work I rush into the
想着工作的事情。我匆匆走进
living room sometimes I'll like say
客厅，有时我会
hello to her then I'll go on my laptop
跟她打个招呼，然后打开笔记本电脑
and I start working and she comes over
开始工作。这时她走过来跟
and says something to me and because I'm
我说话，因为我
focused on my work I either acknowledge
专注于工作，所以我要么只是回应
her but without turning my head or
她，但不会转头；
sometimes I'll just give one sec babee
有时我会只是等一下，说“亲爱的，
I'm busy or say something words to that
我很忙”，或者说一些类似的话。
effect right it's clearly causing a
这显然会造成
problem I'm I'm guilty of the same
问题。我也犯过同样的错误。
thing I was working on a on a book uh
我当时正在写一本书，
and Julie said you know I go into the
朱莉说……你知道吗？ 我走进
living room and sit down and you don't
客厅坐下，你
even look up and I sit there for a while
甚至都没抬头看我一眼。我坐了一会儿，
and then I get up and leave and you
然后起身离开，你都没
haven't even noticed that I was there so
注意到我来过。所以我也有同样的
I was guilty of it too turning away and
毛病，总是转过身去。我们努力改正了，确实努力过。还有一点，
other thing too though with John and
关于约翰，我逐渐
I've I've learned to accept this right
学会了接受。
over time is that John grew up in a
约翰小时候是
refugee in New York City and it was loud
难民，住在纽约市一间非常小的公寓里，那里很
and noisy and there were a lot of people
吵闹，人也很多，
all around so he had to develop this
所以他必须培养出惊人的专注力。
incredible sense of concentration and so
所以，
when I first met you it was so funny
当我第一次见到你的时候，
John um I would be across the kitchen
约翰，那件事真的很有趣。我坐在厨房的料理
counter from John he would be reading a
台对面，约翰在看书，他甚至
book he wouldn't even be on his computer
都没用电脑，而是在
be reading a book and I would say
看书。我会说：“
John uh
约翰，
John hey John and I would wave my hand
嘿，约翰。”然后我会挥挥手，
and finally he would say oh yeah I
最后他会说：“哦，是啊，我真的没听到。”他
really didn't hear it he didn't hear it
真的没听到，我是说真的没听到。
I mean literally and I had
我必须
to understand that with that kind of
理解，在那种
concentration he really didn't hear me
专注力下，他真的没听到我说话。
how did it make you feel how did it make
你当时是什么感觉？我又是什么
me feel at first it made me feel
感觉？ 一开始，这让我感觉自己像个
invisible
隐形人，
unimportant um
不重要，不被爱，被拒绝，
unloved rejected alone you know it made
孤独无助。你知道，这让
me feel all kinds of stuff until I
我感觉五味杂陈，直到我
understood wait a minute there's
明白，等等，
something in his
他的
brain that's very different than my
大脑里肯定有什么东西和我的
brain because I'm always you know I have
大脑很不一样，因为我总是……你知道，我感觉自己像个“
no skin I'm like super aware of
皮肤”，对
everything around me okay so John give
周围的一切都异常敏感。好吧，约翰，
me some advice then from your studies in
根据你在爱情实验室的研究，给我一些建议吧。
the love lab if my partner makes a bid
如果我的伴侣试图与我建立
for connection yeah what are the ways
联系，
that people typically respond and how
人们通常会如何回应？
should I respond when you looked at the
我应该如何回应？当你研究那些
the long term um how do they respond how
长期关系最成功的伴侣时，他们是如何回应的？
should I respond give me some advice
我应该如何回应？给我一些建议吧。是的，
yeah I think I I think the really great
我认为真正美好的
relationships have this motto that when
关系都有一个共同的准则：当
their partner is upset you just stop
伴侣难过时，你要停下手头的
everything you're doing and listen and I
一切，认真倾听。
I keep a notebook in my back pocket just
我会在后口袋里放一个笔记本，就是
for that purpose so if Julie says we
为了这个目的。所以如果朱莉说我们
need to talk I whip out my notebook my
需要谈谈，我会立刻拿出笔记本
pen and I say okay I'm taking notes so
和笔，说：“好的，我在记笔记，
I'm ready to listen to her and you know
我已经准备好倾听她了。” 你知道，
it's true that sometimes I'm oblivious
有时候我确实会对
to what's going on around me but you
周围发生的事情浑然不觉，但你
know I I become much more aware so when
知道，我会变得更加敏锐。所以当……
she comes into the living room now I I
她现在走进客厅，我
stop what I'm doing close the computer
停下手里的事，关掉电脑，
and say how you doing what's on your
问她：“你好吗？有什么
mind my my issue is with that is I work
心事吗？”我的问题是，我
in the living room sometimes so what's
有时会在客厅工作，所以如何在不
interrupted while also not rejecting my
被打扰的情况下，既能在客厅或类似的公共空间工作，又不至于无意中或有意地冷落我的
partner accidentally or you know lowkey
伴侣，找到一个平衡点呢？
intentionally I I think the solution is
我认为解决办法是
to create a ritual around connection you
建立一种沟通的仪式，
know so if she if she really needs to
这样，如果她真的需要和我
talk to you she can you know give you a
谈谈，她就可以给我一个
signal that it's important for her to
信号，告诉我她觉得
connect with you and then it's not
和你沟通很重要。而且，这种仪式不会
always happening you know it's just
总是发生，它只会在真正
happening when it's important and
重要的时候发生。
Julie's like that too so she'll you know
朱莉也是这样，
she'll come in and she won't sit there
她会进来，不会坐在那里等
and and just wait for me to respond
我回应，而是会主动说：“
she'll actually go we need to talk and
我们需要谈谈。”
then I know I get my notebook out but
然后我就会拿出笔记本。但是
let me point out something though honey
亲爱的，我想指出一点，
you're you're talking only about you
你说的好像只是
know if I'm upset about something so I
我心情不好，所以才
have to work in the living room also of
需要在客厅工作的情况，
our house um or John may be working in
或者约翰可能…… 我在
the living room and if he's working on
客厅工作，如果他正在忙
something and I want his
什么，而我想让他
attention I may ask him can I have your
听我说几句，我可能会问他：“我可以占用你一会儿吗？
attention for a moment so I need to say
我需要
what I need to him and if it's something
跟他说点事。”如果是些琐事，
that's trivial and he says just a minute
他说：“等一下，
you know I'm working on an email or
我在处理邮件什么的。”好的，没问题。
whatever okay that's fine you know our
我们俩的
timing is not going to be identical he's
时间安排不可能完全一样，他也不可能随时都有空。
won't be either right and so we try to
所以我会尽量互相
inquire of one another is this a good
询问对方现在是否方便
time for us to talk and there's
谈话。当然，
sometimes when it's not a good time for
有时候确实不方便
you to talk John of course right of
谈话，约翰，对吧？当然，
course that's where I think I've
我觉得我在这方面比较
struggled because sometimes I feel like
挣扎，因为有时候我觉得
this is not a good time to talk and I
现在不方便谈话，我
express that and I think maybe the way
表达…… 我觉得
that I'm expressing it isn't soft enough
我表达的方式可能不够温柔。
maybe I'm you know let me give you one
你知道，让我告诉你我
of my favorite things to say okay which
最喜欢说的一句话，好吗？
is honey I would really love to listen
亲爱的，我
to you right now but I really am feeling
现在真的很想听你说话，但我真的感觉
pressured to finish this so can you just
压力很大，必须尽快完成这件事，所以你能
wait however amount of time you know 30
等我一会儿吗？30
minutes or an hour and then I'll be able
分钟或者1小时都行，之后我就可以
to give you my full
全心全意地听你说话了。你
attention see that I want to listen to
看，我想听
you that's the key phrase that tells
你说话，这句话很关键，它告诉
your partner I value you I love you but
你的伴侣：我重视你，我爱你，但我
there's pressure on me right now too so
现在也有压力，所以
please be understanding and I'll be
请你理解，我会尽快赶到你身边。
there for you as soon as I can be you
你
know in the in the love lab when you saw
知道，在“爱情实验室”里，你看到
these couples who were missing bids for
一些情侣错过了建立
connection so for the example you gave
联系的机会。比如你举的例子，
Julie of someone looking out the window
朱莉，有人看着窗外
and saying babe come and look at this
说：“宝贝，过来看看这个”，
and then the other person either ignores
然后另一个人要么忽略
it or kind of dismisses it was that
它，要么敷衍了事。约翰，是那
individual who dismissed it or ignored
个人故意忽略或敷衍的吗？还是因为
of something that's caused them to sort
某些事情的积累，导致他们
of passively reject the person or was it
被动地拒绝了对方？
they were just oblivious yeah it's
他们是不是真的没注意到？是啊，这
really hard to know I mean the one thing
真的很难说。我的意思是，
I can tell you was the person who got
我能告诉你的一点是，被拒绝的人会有点
turned away from kind of crumples a
沮丧。
little bit so regardless of the reason
所以，不管
for the turning away if it's really
拒绝的原因是什么，如果这真的成了
habitual
习惯，那么
that person making a bid really gets
出价的人真的会因为被
hurt by the turning away
拒绝
and and that I think leads people to
而感到受伤。我认为这会导致人们
stop
停止
bidding you know to think you know
出价，你知道，他们会想，你知道，还有什么
what's the point and then what happens
意义呢？然后会发生什么呢？
well then they they just create this
他们会制造
emotional distance yeah uh and put up
情感上的距离，筑起心
walls and then what happens and then
墙。然后会发生什么呢？然后会发生什么呢？
what happens is that they become lonely
他们会变得孤独。
and then what happens quite often an
然后经常会发生的情况是，
fair oh they cheat or okay yeah
他们会作弊，或者最终……是的，
eventually and it all starts with
这一切都始于
missing a bid for connection potentially
错过一次建立联系的出价，
and that becoming a habit many of them
这可能成为一种习惯。是的，是的，
yeah yeah you know I I like to use the
你知道，我喜欢用
metaphor of a sea anemon you know what
海葵来做比喻，你知道海葵
that's like right it's a little sea
是什么样的吗？它是一种生活
creature in a tile pool that that has
在瓷砖池子里的小海洋生物，有很多细小的
all these little fingers all these
触手。
little fingers so it may be relaxing
它可能会放松
those fingers and opening up and
这些触手，张开身体，
revealing its
露出
underbelly but when somebody refuses a
腹部。但是，当有人拒绝建立
bid for connection it's as if that
联系的出价时，就好像这只
little C anomy has been poked right in
小海葵…… 被戳到
the stomach and so all the fingers close
肚子上，所有的触手都
up and shut down and lock down and it
闭合、关闭、锁定，海葵
takes a much longer time for that anemon
需要很长时间才能
to unfold its fingers again and be open
再次展开触手。
yeah it's not safe mhm did you ever find
嗯，这不安全。嗯，你有没有发现过？
and I think this is something that I've
我觉得这跟我
talked about before on my relationship
之前在感情方面说过，
that sometimes when I miss a bid for
有时候我错过一次
connection it increases the amounts of
联系的尝试，反而会增加她
bids for connection because I think I'm
联系的次数。我觉得
guessing that I'm a bit of an avoidant
我有点回避
type based on my history in my childhood
型，这跟我童年的经历有关。
she's a little bit more of an anxious
她则有点焦虑
type so it seems to be the case that if
型。所以，如果
I say not now babe I'm working then the
我说“宝贝，现在不行，我在工作”，她
amount of bids increase and they they
联系的次数就会增加。然后，她开始……在我
opinion and I could be well wrong here
看来，我可能错了，她
they they're not they're not actually
其实并没有……
window now it becomes more about trying
现在，她只是想
to confirm whether I it's a test right
确认这是否是一种考验，对吧？
it's a test yeah that's it feels like a
是的，感觉像是一种
test yeah right right but also what it
考验。对，对，对。但当……
is when especially when there isn't
尤其是在没有其他事情发生的时候，其实
is very pure and simple I need to
很简单，我需要
connect with you I need to feel that
联系。 我需要和你感受到那种
connection sure I can imagine it I can
联结。当然，我可以想象，我还能
remember it from you know 3 hours ago
回忆起三个小时前的感觉，
but right now I'm feeling that kind of
但现在我内心深处涌起一股莫名的渴望，
and I want to connect with you I just
我想和你联结，我就是
need that
需要这种
connection so she's attempting to create
联结。所以她试图创造这种联结。
that what is this
什么是“
attune framework John
协调框架”？约翰，
attune awareness turning toward
协调意识转向
tolerance understanding n defensive
宽容、理解和防御性共情。
empathetic what is this framework yeah
这个框架是什么？是的，“
Attunement is really uh you know it's
协调”
like two Musical instruments that really
就像两件乐器
are tuned to one another and when one
彼此调音，一件
plays the other resonates so uh creating
演奏时，另一件会共鸣。所以，创造
rituals of connection you know like we
联结的仪式，你知道，就像我们
have a ritual every morning you know
每天早上都有一个仪式，
where you know I'll say I'll ask Julie
我会问朱莉：“
you know what's on your play today what
你今天有什么安排？
you know what's your day look like and
你今天过得怎么样？”
she'll say what what does your day look
她会回答：“你今天过得怎么样？”
like so we kind of check in with with
我们就这样互相了解彼此的近况。
each other and then at dinner we have
然后在晚餐时，我们还有
another ritual connection and you know
一个联结仪式，我们会问：“你
how was your day you know what what
今天过得怎么样？
happened how did that how did that
发生了什么事？那次
session go and we kind of keep in touch
会议进行得如何？”我们
with each other with these structured
用这些结构化的
ways of attuning and in that way you
方式保持联系。 通过协调，你们就
don't lose touch you don't make
不会失去联系，也不会妄下
assumptions you know we ask each other
断言。我们会互相问一些
questions like what can I do this week
问题，比如“这周我能做些什么
to make you feel loved and you know when
让你感受到爱？”。当
you have that kind of ritual then you
你们有这样的仪式感时，你们就建立了
know you know you're connecting and um
联系。
and you're like those two instruments
你们就像两件
that are tuned to each other may I add a
彼此调谐的乐器。我还要补充
little to that um empathy is super super
一点，同理心非常非常
important and I I honestly believe that
重要，我真心相信，
empathy is probably the most powerful
同理心可能是
tool we have to really create connection
我们建立彼此联系的最有力工具。
with one another so if our partner is
所以，如果我们的伴侣
saying to us I'm really upset right now
对你说：“我现在真的很沮丧，我很生气，因为
I'm really angry that I'm doing all the
所有的
housework can you attune to that can you
家务都是我做的。”你能理解她的感受吗？你可以
say first of all tell me more what what
说：“首先，请告诉我更多，是什么让你觉得这是
is making that a burden for you so
负担？”这样
you're pulling information out and then
你就能从她那里获取信息。然后
your partner might be saying well you
你的伴侣可能会说：“你
know it's like the second shift for me
知道，这就像我的第二个班，
I'm at work all day and then I have to
我白天上班，
come home and clean the house Etc so I
回家还要打扫房子等等。所以我
want to share that with you okay can you
想和你分享一下。”你能
empathize with her can you say ah no
理解她吗？你可以说：“啊，
wonder you're probably pretty tired when
难怪。” 你回家的时候可能很累吧？
you come home right so you really do
所以你真的
need my support is that what you're
需要我的支持，是吗？
trying to tell me mhm that's the
嗯，这就是所谓的“协调”。
Attunement you see I was going to say
你看，我本来想说
it's quite difficult isn't it because it
这很难，不是吗？因为它
often sounds like blame here's the
听起来常常像是在指责。区别就在这里，
difference there's a big difference and
区别很大，
this is what we saw in the lab also it
这也是我们在实验室里看到的。当
what your partner is saying for example
你的伴侣说的话里有很多“你”的成分时，那就是指责。比如，
you never clean up the kitchen you are
你从来不收拾厨房，你
too lazy to do any housework at the end
太懒了，一天下来什么家务都不想做，那
of the day what about me you know Etc so
我呢？等等。在
with that kind of blaming and criticism
这种指责和批评中，没有
nobody nobody is going to feel like oh
人会觉得“哦，
you're absolutely right you're really
你说得对，你真的很生
mad at me because I've been a schmuck
我的气，因为我太笨了，
and I haven't been helping you with the
我没有帮你做
housework and that's what you're telling
家务”，而你却在这样告诉
me no what people have to do when
我。不，当人们因为
they're unhappy about something is
某件事不开心时，他们需要做的是
describe
描述
themselves I'm
自己。我因为
upset that what's the situation describe
什么事感到难过？描述一下
the situation I'm upset that the kitchen
情况。我因为厨房
is a mess okay that the kitchen is a
乱糟糟而难过。好的，厨房
mess is a situation it's not saying
乱糟糟就是一个情况。 这并不是说
you're a bad person you see and then
你是个坏人，你看。
step three they need to say what their
第三步，他们需要说出自己的
positive need is which means how can
积极需求，也就是
your partner Shine for you don't tell
你的伴侣如何才能为你闪耀光芒。不要告诉
them what they they're not doing right
他们他们哪里做得不对，
or what you resent flip that on its head
或者你有什么不满，而是反过来
and say I would love it if you would
说，比如“如果你
help me tonight with the dishes my
今晚能帮我洗碗，我会非常开心”。我的
partner did that yesterday actually she
伴侣昨天就这么做了，
um and I I noticed that she did it so
嗯，我注意到她这么做了。
basically she's in Costa Rica right now
她现在在哥斯达黎加
doing a retreat and she sent me a text
参加一个静修活动，她给我发短信说：“
saying babe I love it when you tell me
亲爱的，我喜欢
how the podcast went after you finished
你录完播客后告诉我情况。” 这句话有很
recording it now there's several ways
多种表达方式，比如，
that someone could have said that she
她
could have said I hate it when you don't
可以说“我讨厌你不
tell me for example that's right but she
告诉我”，没错，但她
said I love it when you tell me what
说的是“我喜欢你告诉我”。她的意思是让我
she's telling me is to do it more and it
多这样做，
I felt it to be really motivating that
我觉得这真的很有激励作用，
I'll do it more so I started doing it
所以我开始多这样做，在
voice notes after the podcast but I've
播客结束后给她发语音留言。但我
also seen it in relationships where it's
也见过一些关系中，这种表达方式被
fra framed the it's trying to get the
包装成……它试图……
same outcome but it's framed in the
结果一样，但表达方式却截然
opposite way it's negative it's I
相反，是负面的。我
suddenly feel like I'm on the back foot
突然感觉自己处于劣势，好像
and I've done something wrong and I'm a
做错了什么，就像个
child being told off by my mother or
孩子被妈妈训斥一样。没错，就是这样。
something right exactly and what is your
你对
first response to that defensiveness uh
这种防御心理的第一反应是什么？嗯……
uh deny it throw it back on them exactly
否认，反击回去。没错，是的。
yep and that's one of the predictors you
这是关系不幸福的预测因素之一，虽然
know a smaller predictor but still a
预测因素较小，但仍然是
predictor of relationship
预测因素之一。
John in your opinion well you know it's
约翰，你认为典型的伴侣治疗为什么会失败？嗯，你知道，现在
not failing very much anymore there are
失败的情况已经不多见了，
some very good approaches now some
现在有一些非常好的方法，一些
behavioral approaches that are working
行为疗法效果
pretty well and emotionally focused
很好，情绪聚焦
therapy is working much better so things
疗法也效果显著，所以情况有所
have improved um but I think typically
改善。但我认为，通常情况下，治疗
the reason that it fails is that the
失败的原因是
therapist doesn't really have the proper
治疗师缺乏
tools for either assessing a
评估
relationship and most therapists don't
关系的合适工具。大多数治疗师在
do any assessment when a couple comes in
伴侣来咨询时根本不做任何评估，
they don't look for you know what are
他们不会去寻找
the strengths in this relationship and
这段关系的优势是什么，哪些方面
what do I not need to work on and what
不需要努力，哪些
are the challenges that I really need to
挑战是真正需要
work on and not only don't they
努力的。 他们
typically assess but once once they
通常不会进行评估，但一旦
start working with a couple they don't
开始与伴侣合作，他们就
really have the tools as I heard with
缺乏必要的工具。我听说，
therapy it's all about listening you
治疗的关键在于倾听。
know and the stat I'm I'm citing here is
我引用的数据是，
that um traditional couples therapy only
传统的伴侣治疗
had a 35 to 50% success rate right and
成功率只有35%到50%。
you typically think of therapy like you
你通常认为治疗就是你
go there and your job is just to listen
去那里，你的任务就是倾听
to your partner as they tell you what's
伴侣诉说他们的
wrong yeah why doesn't that work because
问题。为什么这种方法行不通呢？因为
they're telling you typically what's
他们通常告诉你的是你
wrong with you and the therapist isn't
自己的问题，而治疗师并没有
stopping them isn't saying that's
阻止他们，也没有指出这是
criticism that's not going to work that
批评，批评是无效的，会
is going to sabotage you getting
破坏你被
listened to so try this instead try
倾听的过程。所以，试试这样做：试着
telling your partner what you feel and
告诉你的伴侣你的感受和
what you need instead of describing your
需求，而不是描述你的
partner and what's wrong with him I
伴侣以及他/她哪里出了问题。我亲眼
actually saw at a conference I'm not
在一个会议上看到，我没
making this up somebody was training
编故事，有人在培训
therapists and this this therapist who
治疗师，这位培训师
was doing the training played a
播放了一段
videotape in which a husband said to his
录像，录像中一位丈夫对妻子说：“
wife you know Sheila you're such a
希拉，你真是个贱人，
you only think about yourself and the
你只想着自己。”
therapist said Sheila can you summarize
治疗师说…… 希拉，你能总结
and reflect back what Harry just said
一下哈里刚才说的话，
and empathize with
并试着理解
him I
他吗？我当时
thought God you know what an idiot I
想，天哪，他真是个白痴。我的
mean nobody can
意思是，没人能
empathize with insult and put Downs you
理解这种侮辱和贬低别人的行为。你
know why isn't she constraining the way
知道吗，为什么希拉不制止
Harry's talking to Sheila not just
哈里跟她说话的方式？
Sheila listening so I think a lot of
希拉只是在听而已。我觉得很多
times therapists really don't know how
时候，治疗师真的不知道怎么
to use a tool they don't know what
用工具，他们不知道什么
really is appropriate what a good
是真正合适的，也不知道一段好的
relationship looks like I'm really Keen
关系应该是什么样的。我真的很想
to understand the principles of what
了解
successful couples do from your research
成功伴侣的原则。从你的研究中，
you've highlighted a few of those things
你已经强调了一些。
I mean you've got the seven principles
我的意思是，你提出了
of success marriage what are some of the
婚姻成功的七项原则，其中最重要的几项是什么？
of all um we call the first principle
首先，我们把第一项原则叫做“
building love Maps you need to keep
构建爱的地图”。你需要不断地
asking your partner open-ended questions
问你的伴侣一些开放式的问题，
to know who they are open-ended
来了解他们是什么样的人。开放式的
questions are questions like
问题就像这样：
so what characteristic would you like to
你想把家族的哪些特质
pass down from your family to our child
传承给我们的孩子？
or what would be your ideal way of
或者你理想的
celebrating Ramadan or Christmas or
庆祝斋月、圣诞节或
whatever holiday so you're asking your
其他节日的方式是什么？你要问你的
partner questions with answers that have
伴侣一些问题，答案要像段落一样完整，而
paragraphs not a one-word answer in
不是一成不变。
order to keep in touch with who your
为了保持与
partner is what their values are what
伴侣的联系，了解他们的价值观、
their priorities are what their needs
优先事项、需求和
are what their feelings are because
感受，请用一个词来回答。因为
those change over time as you're
随着时间的推移，这些都会发生变化。正如
together turning toward we talked about
我们之前讨论过的，
that was super important expressing
表达
fondness and admiration is very
喜爱和欣赏非常
important so you can feel love and if
重要，这样你才能感受到爱。如果
you don't tell your partner you love
你不告诉伴侣你爱
them or express it with touch which is
他们，或者不通过肢体接触来表达爱意（这
incredibly
非常
important then your partner may not be
重要），那么五年后，你的伴侣可能就不
all that sure that you still do love
确定你是否还爱着
them 5 years down the road of course
他们。当然，
managing conflict is incredibly
处理冲突也极其
important and that's where we've
重要，这
probably done our most significant work
可能是我们做得最重要的部分。
but in addition to that it's honoring
除此之外，还要尊重
each other's
彼此的
dreams dreams meaning what are your
梦想。梦想指的是你对
hopes and aspirations for the future
未来的希望和抱负。
they're not going to be compatible
它们不一定完全一致，也不一定
identical it doesn't matter can you
相同，但这并不重要。你能否
support your partner in realizing their
支持你的伴侣实现他们的
own dream and fulfilling that and
梦想并最终实现它？
finally creating shared meaning which
最后，创造共同的意义，这
means every one of us is a philosopher
意味着我们每个人都是哲学家，
we have our own ideas about what our
我们对人生的意义都有自己的看法。那么，
purpose in life is well do you tell your
你是否告诉你的
partner what that is for you and you
伴侣你的人生意义是什么？你是否能从
hear that from your partner that's the
你的伴侣那里听到同样的答案？
needed and the weightbearing walls and
需要分享，需要搭建起承重墙，当然还需要
trust and commitment of course so trust
信任和承诺。信任需要
builds over time and trust is
时间积累，它
essentially answering the question will
本质上是在回答这个问题：
you be there for me in all kinds of
在各种不同的情况下，你会在我身边吗？
for me when I'm sick when I'm depressed
当我生病时，当我沮丧时，
when I want to celebrate a success when
当我想要庆祝成功时，当
I'm frustrated will you be there for me
我感到挫败时，你会在我身边吗？
and nobody will be perfectly but the
没有人能做到完美，但
more the better so that's
越多越好。这就是
trust and commit of course is are you
信任，而承诺当然也意味着你
letting your partner know that this
要让你的伴侣知道，这段
relationship is your journey for life
关系是你们一生的旅程，
you are here for life not for you know
你们要在一起一辈子，而不是只维持
the next three weeks and then you'll
三周，然后你们再重新
think about it again why is
考虑。为什么
having expressed dreams so important
表达梦想如此重要？
because I often think that about sort of
因为我经常思考这个问题，关于
my relationship I think our dreams are
我的关系，我认为我们的梦想
not the same they're very different and
并不相同，它们截然不同。
sometimes I wonder and I've wondered and
有时我会想，而且我也一直在想，
I think we've both wondered in my
在我的关系中，我们俩都思考过，
relationship whether that is a big big
这是否是一个大
issue if it matters but why is it so
问题，或者它是否重要。但是，为什么
important to express your dreams to your
向你的伴侣表达你的梦想如此重要？
partner and do do they have to be
它们必须
aligned okay number one they don't have
一致吗？首先，它们不必
to be aligned that's one of the big
一致，这是一直
myths of all time you have to be
以来最大的误区之一。你必须……
compatible you have to have the same
合拍意味着拥有相同的
dreams the same passions the same
梦想、相同的热情、相同的
interest wrong wrong wrong that's not
兴趣——错！错！错！这根本不是
true in fact often times were attracted
真的。事实上，我们常常会被与
to people who were different from us
我们不同的人所吸引。
Conflict though so if one partner's
但是，当梦想发生冲突时会发生什么呢？比如，如果一方的
dreams is to live in Australia and the
梦想是生活在澳大利亚，而
other partner's dream is to live on on
另一方的梦想是生活在
America you know there are certain
美国，那么在某些
situations where one person's dream is
情况下，一个人的梦想可能是
the other person's Nightmare and they're
另一个人的噩梦，他们之间
they really don't have a compromise
根本无法达成妥协。
that's possible so the one you described
你描述的那种情况，
I had a couple like that where she lived
我之前就遇到过一对这样的情侣。女方住
in Switzerland he lived in Uganda she
在瑞士，男方住在乌干达。她
had an autistic son and that autistic
有一个自闭症儿子，这个
son needed desperately a very good
儿子迫切需要一个良好的
support system to help him cope with the
支持系统来帮助他应对
differences that he lived with every day
每天面临的各种挑战。
so she wanted to stay in Switzerland he
女方想留在瑞士，男方在
worked for the government in Uganda he
乌干达政府工作，为
was making a contribution there he did
当地做出贡献，他
not want to move to Switzerland and she
不想搬到瑞士。女方也知道，如果搬到瑞士，
knew she wouldn't get the support for
她
herself son in Uganda so they had
自己和儿子都得不到所需的支持。所以，他们的
incompatible totally incompatible dreams
梦想完全不相容，完全不相容，
but there was no compromise here so they
但他们之间没有任何妥协的余地。
ended up breaking up but they knew why
最终，他们分手了，但他们知道
they were breaking up and it was for
分手的原因，而且是彻底的分手。
good reason are some problems solvable
原因在于，有些问题可以解决，
then and some problems not solvable yeah
有些问题则无法解决。事实
it turns out 69% of all problems are not
证明，69%的问题都
solvable and just you know we're not
无法解决。你知道，我们通常不会被和
attracted to people who are like us and
自己相似的人吸引，但
then once we get together we find those
一旦在一起，就会发现彼此的
differences although initially very
差异，虽然最初很有吸引力，但
spontaneous but then why can't he ever
后来却很烦人。所以，他如此随性固然很好，但为什么他总是无法
stick to a
坚持
plan you know and that becomes a source
计划呢？这最终会成为
of irritation and unless people can
令人恼火的根源。除非人们能够
really be enriched by those differences
真正从这些差异中汲取养分，
and learn to accept the differences
并学会接受它们，否则
they're going to be in a lot of trouble
他们将会遇到很多麻烦。
so when we looked at over time at what
当我们长期观察
people fought about it was 69% of the
人们争吵的原因时，发现69%的
time it was the same issues and what you
情况下都是同样的问题，也就是
you call these Perpetual problems
所谓的“
Perpetual problems yeah and once you
永恒问题”。一旦你
pick somebody to have a relationship
选择与某人建立恋爱关系，你
with you've automatically inherited the
就自动继承了
problems you'll have for the next 50
未来50
years these are problems you can't solve
年将要面对的问题。这些问题你无法
really right but you can adapt to them
真正解决，但你可以适应它们，
and laugh about them and compromise
一笑置之，并在一些细节上做出妥协。
around the edges okay so what's an
那么，
example of a Perpetual problem in your
你的恋爱关系中是否存在“永恒问题”呢？我的
relationship oh my my God okay so um
天哪！ 好的，
John first of all he's wearing you know
首先，约翰戴着
a a Jewish yam he thinks this is a Halo
一个犹太山药，你知道，他觉得这是个光环，对吧？
right so you know he's
你知道，他
I he's always innocent okay so he calls
总是那么天真无邪。他叫
me obsessively compulsively neurotically
我强迫症式的神经质
tidy and he is charmingly sloppy okay so
洁癖，而他自己则邋遢得可爱。所以
we have a huge
我们之间有很大的
difference and so
差异，
um here's how we've coped with it
以下是我们应对这种差异的方法：
because environment is not it's just not
环境对
important for him and for me it's super
他来说并不重要，但对我来说却非常
important it will disorganize my mind if
重要。如果
my environment is disorganized so when
我的环境杂乱无章，我的思绪就会混乱。所以，当
things start to get to me there's too
事情开始让我感到烦躁的时候，比如
much mess too many papers books I can't
太乱、太多纸张和书籍，我根本没法
make the bed because I'm trying to lean
铺床，因为我得弯腰
over a 4ot tall pile of books and I may
越过一堆四英尺高的书，
break my neck if I try to make the bed
如果我试图铺床，我的脖子可能会断掉。
so it gets to that point and then I'll
所以，当情况发展到那种地步时，我会对
say to him honey I really need you to
他说：“亲爱的，我真的需要你把
please clean up the books in the bedroom
卧室里的书收拾一下。”
he'll say okay then he won't do it then
他会说“好的”，然后他又不会去做。然后
I'll ask the next week I'll say honey
下周我再问他：“亲爱的，
it's you know I'm I'm really wanting you
你知道，我真的需要你……”  “你把
to clean this up please he said okay I
这些收拾干净好吗？”他说。“好的，我
will but then he has to I don't know do
会的。”但之后他又不得不……我不知道，去做点
something else so it doesn't happen week
别的事，所以这件事才没发生。到了
three I say to him
第三周，我对他说：“
okay honey I've said this now twice I'm
好了亲爱的，我已经说过两遍了，我
starting to get annoyed he'll say oh
开始有点不耐烦了。”他会说：“哦，好的，
okay all right I'll think I I'll figure
我会想办法的。”到了
four we're counting down I say okay
第四周，我们开始倒计时了。我说：“好了，
we've crossed the threshold I'm now
我们已经过了那个阶段了，我现在很
Angry I really need you to clean up the
生气，我真的需要你
books now please and I become a pushy
现在就把书收拾干净，拜托了。”然后我就变成了一个咄咄逼人的
Jewish Broad that's what happens and he
犹太女人，事情就是这样。他“哦”了一声，然后
oh and he says okay okay because I'm
说：“好的，好的。”因为我比
bigger than he is and I had two older
他块头大，我有两个
brothers and I'm really good at
哥哥，而且我
wrestling and stuff and so I clean it up
摔跤什么的也很厉害，所以我就收拾干净了。
he cleans it up really fast it's
他收拾得很快，干净得一尘不染，很
pristine it's beautiful I savor it then
漂亮。我好好享受了一番，然后一切又重新
it starts over again so how do we is
开始了。所以我们该如何
that the pathway to dealing with
应对这种
Perpetual problems is you just have to
永无止境的问题呢？难道解决之道就是
like accept them that it's going
接受它们吗？
to so here's the deal with Perpetual
这就是解决永无止境
problems we have a method for compromise
问题的关键：我们有一种妥协的方法，
we call it the bagel method or maybe the
我们称之为…… 可以用百吉饼法，或者
donut method depending on your culture
甜甜圈法，这取决于你的文化。
okay so in an inner circle you think
好的，在内圈，你要
about or you write down what can you not
思考或写下你在立场上哪些方面不能
compromise on in terms of your position
妥协，你在
your position on this issue what what
这个问题上的立场是什么，哪些方面
can you not it would be like giving up
你不能妥协，就像放弃
the bones of your body or that core
你的骨骼，或者放弃你的核心
dream you have that is so Central to
梦想一样，那是
your identity that you got to hold on to
你身份认同的核心，你必须坚持下去。
that then in an Outer Circle you write
然后在外圈，你要
down what you're more flexible about and
写下你在哪些方面比较灵活，
those are typically when something will
通常是事情何时
happen who will do it where it will
发生、由谁来做、在哪里发生、花费
happen how much will it cost how long
多少、持续多久等等
will it last those nitty-gritty Det
这些
details you share what you've written
细节。你要
down in both circles with your partner
和你的伴侣分享你在两个圈里写下的内容，
and you look at the flexible areas
然后你们要审视
around each of your positions on the
各自立场中可以灵活调整的部分，
issue and you try to reach a compromise
尝试就
regarding those
这些
flexible points of view while still
灵活的观点达成妥协，同时
honoring each other's inner core dream
尊重彼此的核心梦想
or core need but you must want to change
或需求。但是你肯定想改变
that about John right you must want to
约翰的那个习惯，对吧？你肯定想
change of course I want to change it but
改变，我当然想改变。但
you know what John wouldn't be John if
你知道吗，如果约翰
he was a tidy neat guy and after a time
是个爱干净整洁的人，那他就不是约翰了。过了一段时间，
it's just
这真的很
adorable it's funny and we have such a
可爱，很有趣，而且我们 你们的
wonderful relationship that it's
关系如此美好，以至于既
hilarious and it's predictable you need
滑稽又可预测，但你们需要
to talk about gridlocked Perpetual
谈谈陷入僵局的长期
problems that's a whole different story
问题，这完全是另一回事。
that's a different story so gridlock is
僵局指的是
when you cannot die dialogue about
你们无法就
something because you hold so fast to
某个问题进行对话，因为你们对
your own position on the issue that you
自己在这个问题上的立场过于固执，你们
really want to win this battle it's not
真的想赢得这场争论，这不是
a matter of compromise you know you're
妥协的问题，你知道自己是对的，
right you want to win and the other
你想赢，而
person feels the same way then what you
对方也有同样的想法。然后，你们
try to talk without really listening to
试图在没有真正倾听
one another and understanding at a much
对方、没有进行
deeper level which is part of our work
更深层次的理解的情况下进行对话，而这正是我们工作的一部分。理解
what really constitutes our partner's
伴侣的
position why they holding that position
立场，理解他们为什么如此坚定地持有这种立场，理解了他们的立场，理解了
strongly and with your understanding
理解会
comes more compassion if you don't have
带来更多的同情。如果你缺乏
that understanding if you're trying to
这种理解，如果你一心只想
win you get gridlocked to the point
赢，你们就会陷入僵局，
where every fight escalates to the
每次争吵都会升级到
ceiling you end up yelling or you shut
极限，最终你会大吼大叫，或者干脆沉默不语，把问题藏起来，
down shove it under the rug but you can
但
feel it as you walk around the living
你走在客厅里仍然能感觉到。
room this this is I mean this is one of
这就是
the big problems in relationships John
人际关系中的一个大问题，约翰，那就是
is that we often feel like our partner
我们常常觉得伴侣
is trying to change Us in ways that we
试图以我们无法接受的方式改变我们。 我
don't want to be changed that's right
不想改变，没错，
and I often I've been in a relationship
而且我经常……我
before past relationship where my
以前谈过恋爱，上一段感情中，我的
partner would say things that were an
伴侣会说一些…… 她
attempt to change me but in doing so she
试图改变我，但
was actually telling me that she didn't
实际上她是在告诉我，她
think I was good enough right oh you see
觉得我不够好，对吧？哦，你明白
what I'm saying sure well that's that's
我的意思吧？当然，这就是
the nature of gridlock conflict yeah and
僵局冲突的本质。是的，
and part of what what we've done is
我们所做的一部分工作是
invent six
设计了六个
questions that 87% of the time work to
问题，这些问题在87%的情况下都能帮助
get people out of gridlock where they
人们摆脱僵局。
they're asking these questions about
他们会问这些问题：你
what does this feel like what does this
感觉如何？你觉得这次谈话是什么感觉？
that you think I'm trying to change
你认为我试图改变
about you and that I don't think is good
你什么，而我认为你做得不够好？
enough tell me how that feels and what's
告诉我你的感受，
your ideal dream of how we should talk
你理想中的谈话方式是什么？你觉得这种想法从何而来？你
that come from and you know where is it
觉得我
that you feel unaccepted by me so if you
不接受你的原因是什么？如果你
can have that conversation a lot of
能进行这样的对话，很多
times you develop the sense of
时候你们就能建立起
understanding and then you can
理解，然后你们就能就
compromise about the gridlock this year
僵局做出妥协。今年，
one of the recurring things I've had in
我在恋爱关系中反复遇到的一个问题
relationships is I'm very involved with
是，我
technology in my work so sometimes it's
的工作非常依赖科技，所以有时
felt in relationships that I've had that
我会觉得
the person is trying to take my work
对方试图剥夺我的工作时间。
away from me so because they're always
因为他们总是
complaining that I'm on my phone or I'm
抱怨我玩手机、玩
on my laptop or whatever thinking like
电脑什么的，好像
they they're trying to change me in a
他们想改变我，但
way that I'm unwilling to change I'm not
我并不想改变。
I I love my work I want to I want that
我热爱我的工作，我希望它成为
to be a big part of my life right how
我生活的重要组成部分，对吧？
how do I go about solving for that so
我该如何解决这个问题？
and that person wants you to do away
而且，那个人有时甚至想让你放弃
with the technology some of the time
科技，对吧？就是这种
how it feels okay so you need to have a
感觉。好吧，所以你们需要进行一次
conversation where each of you
对话，
interviews the other person and asks
互相采访对方，
asks six questions let me go through
问六个问题。我
those just really quickly what are your
快速地过一遍这些问题：你对这个问题的
beliefs values and ethics that are part
信念、价值观和伦理是什么？
of your position on this issue you know
你
wanting to stay with the technology do
希望继续使用科技，
you have some background or childhood
你的背景或童年
history that relates to your
经历与你的立场有关吗？
position why is this so important to you
为什么这件事对你如此重要？你对
what do you feel about your position
自己的立场有何感受？
here what is your ideal dream here what
你的理想是什么？
do you really wish for if the world
你真正希望的是什么？如果世界能如你
could be just like you wanted it
所愿，在
regarding this issue what would it look
这个问题上，它会是什么样子？
important as you answer those questions
在你回答这些问题时，这件事对你来说是否具有重要的意义或目标？ 斯蒂芬，你问她一些问题，让她深入了解
to you regarding this issue then then
你在这个问题上最深层、最重要的东西。然后
you ask her the same questions exactly
你问她同样的问题，
the same ones to understand where she's
一模一样的问题，来理解她的
coming from right and what that creates
立场，对吧？这样做能让你们
compassion for one another about why
彼此更加理解和体谅，明白为什么
each position is so important to that
每个立场对对方如此重要。
partner then you try to work on
然后你们尝试
compromise like I
像我刚才描述的那样达成妥协。很
interesting but those questions are
有意思，但这些问题
fundamental if you just just argue on
至关重要。如果你们只是在
the surface you're not going to get
表面争论，你们将
anywhere you're going to stay gridlocked
一事无成，只会陷入僵局。
I love my work I want to do my work
我热爱我的工作，我只想做我的工作，仅此而已。
period Well does she know why your work
那么她知道为什么你的工作
is so important to you what life purpose
对你如此重要吗？它对你的人生有什么意义？
that is serving for you does she know
她了解你内心深处的本质吗？
in your research you discovered
在你的研究中，你发现了
something which has become pretty iconic
一个
when we talk about relationships and
在谈论人际关系和
conflict which is this idea of the Four
冲突时非常经典的理论，那就是“四
Horsemen um you found that during
骑士”。你发现，在
conflict couples who show four key
冲突中，如果伴侣表现出四种关键
behaviors mean that an argument is
行为，那么争吵就注定
doomed and it's the worst way of arguing
失败，这是最糟糕的争吵方式。
beyond that point John what are the four
约翰，真的，除了争吵之外，什么都得不到。什么是“四
horsemen and how was this discovered
骑士”？你是怎么发现的？是的，
yeah it you know Bob levenson and I uh
你知道的，鲍勃。 我和莱文森
first looked at just the ratio of
首先研究了
positivity to negativity and a conflict
积极与消极的比例以及冲突
discussion and the first thing we
讨论，我们
discovered was that among the Masters
发现，在关系融洽的伴侣中，积极与消极的比例为
that ra IO was 5 to1 or higher and among
5:1或更高，而在关系
the disaster couples it was 8 average 8
破裂的伴侣中，平均比例为8:
to1 what does that mean sorry 5 to1 so
1。这是什么意思呢？抱歉，应该是5:1。所以，
if you take the number of seconds that
如果你统计
they're show displaying interest
他们表现出兴趣、好奇、爱慕、
curiosity affection humor uh shared
幽默、分享
humor validation listening to One
幽默、认可、倾听彼此的时间（比如，
Another uh you know saying things like
说“
no tell me more oh wow oh good point you
不，告诉我更多”、“哦，哇”、“哦，说得对”），然后用这个时间除以
they're angry upset you know
他们表现出愤怒、沮丧、失望、受伤、
disappointed hurt critical defensive
批评、防御、
belligerent you know all these negative
好斗等所有这些负面互动方式的时间（比如，所有这些敌对的互动方式），你会发现，在
conflict during the conflict yeah so but
冲突中相处融洽的伴侣中，积极与消极的比例为5:1或更高。但是，
the second thing we wanted to know is
我们想知道的第二件事是，
well are all negatives equally corrosive
所有负面情绪的腐蚀性都一样吗？
you know and the ones that were the most
最具
corrosive really involved that person
腐蚀性的负面情绪往往是，一方一
starting off and saying you know as far
开始就说“据
as I can tell I'm pretty much fine but
我所知……” 我一切都好，但
you're defective here's what's wrong
你却有缺陷，这就是
with you and they started with this
你的问题所在。他们一开始就以这种自
criticism that they thought was
认为是
constructive criticism you know and they
建设性批评的方式进行批评，
hoped their partner would respond by
希望伴侣会回应说：“
saying you know God you're so insightful
天哪，你真有洞察力，
you know tell me more about how I'm
告诉我我哪里做得
failing but instead what they got was
不好。”但结果却是对方的
defensiveness Counterattack or the
防御、反击，或者摆出一副
innocent victim posture and that was
无辜受害者的姿态。这就是
Apocalypse the third one was contempt
天启四骑士中的第二个，第三个是蔑视，也是最
and that was the worst that was the best
糟糕的，是所有批评中最能
predictor of relationship breakup of all
预示关系破裂的。这种
that criticism from a place of
批评源于一种
superiority I'm better than you you know
优越感：“我比你强，
I you know I I correct your grammar even
你知道吗？我甚至在你生气的时候都会纠正你的语法。”或者“
when you're angry or you know I think
我觉得
I'm more punctual and that's really
我更守时，这很
important or I'm tidier than you are or
重要。”或者“我比你更整洁。”或者“
I'm better informed than you are that
我比你见多识广。”这种
sort of snobbery that you know looking
势利眼，也就是瞧不起
down on their partner may I add
伴侣。我还要补充
something go ahead with contempt also
一点，蔑视也是如此。此外，还有辱骂、讽刺、
mockery sarcasm can have a real Cutting
嘲弄等等。 讽刺有时确实很
Edge it can be funny but then it crosses
犀利，它可能很有趣，但也会
over into hurt and the fourth Horseman
伤人。第四个“骑士”
is stonewalling which was particularly a
是冷暴力，这在
guy thing to do 85% of the time guys
男性中尤为常见。85%的情况下，
with Stonewall they just shut down and
使用冷暴力的男性会完全封闭自己，
they don't give these cues to the
不会给
speaker that they're listening they're
说话者任何回应，比如
not nodding their heads or moving their
点头、
facial muscles or uttering these
面部表情或发出任何
vocalizations like oh you know not doing
声音。他们只是沉默不语，把目光移开。
look away and you know when we found
我们发现，
those people's physiology is really
这些人的生理反应非常
elevated so it wasn't about whether
强烈。所以，这与
couples were arguing or not because we
情侣是否争吵无关，因为我们
typically think a relationship is doomed
通常认为，
if the couple are like screaming at each
如果情侣互相吼叫，这段关系就注定失败。当然，
other again it depends on your
这取决于你对“吼叫”的
definition
定义。
okay so screaming at each other is one
互相吼叫是一种
argument and there are certain couples
争吵的形式，有些情侣
that are volatile where both partners
双方都很情绪化，
are volatile they're very passionate
他们充满激情，情绪非常激动，
they're very intense they may raise
可能会提高
voices but depending on what's coming
音量，但关键在于
out of their mouths is it criticism is
他们说的是什么：是批评、
it contempt is it defensiveness if it's
蔑视还是防御？如果是以上
any of those it's not going to work but
任何一种情况，都可能影响他们的关系。 这行不通，但
you can also scream I'm so Furious about
你也可以大声喊“我对此非常愤怒”，
this still describing yourself that's
同时描述自己，这没什么
not going to be a bad thing why is it
不好。为什么
men you said talked about stonewalling
男人会这样呢？你刚才提到了“冷暴力”，就是那种封闭自己、逃避现实、选择
ignore why is it that men do that more
无视对方的行为。为什么男人
than women well what I think is that we
比女人更容易这样做呢？我认为，我们
men are much more easily physiologically
男人更容易被生理
aroused and the differences are that we
唤起。区别在于，我们
secrete phasal oppression and women
分泌的是催产素，而女人
secrete oxytocin much more than
分泌的催产素远多于
vasopressin and so for us we get once we
加压素。所以，一旦我们
get physiologically aroused it takes us
生理唤起，就需要很
a long time to calm down and most of
长时间才能平静下来。
what we feel when we get physiologically
我们生理唤起时的大部分感受都是
aroused is anger and aggression and we
愤怒和攻击性，我们
want to shut our partner down we're much
想要压制伴侣。我们
more aggressive than women are and so we
比女人更具攻击性，所以我们会选择
shut ourselves down you know and when
封闭自己。当
you look at the dialogue that people
你观察人们冷暴力
have in their minds when they're
时内心的想法，
stonewalling it's usually stuff like
通常会是“
just shut up and don't say anything you
闭嘴，什么都别说”。
know I you know you always make it worse
你知道，你说话只会让情况更糟，所以
when you say something so just be quiet
保持安静，
endure this and that's kind of a male
忍耐一下。 这有点像是男性的
response do men have more of a
反应。男性
physiological response to arguments are
在争论时会有更强烈的生理反应吗？
you like the sweating palms and the
比如手心出汗、
blood pressure you know through
血压升高？要知道，从
Evolution women have been responsible
进化角度来看，女性一直负责
for nurturing an infant in order to do
哺育婴儿。为了做到这一点，
that you have to have a milk letdown
她们必须有泌乳
response right through Evolution so
反射，这是进化的结果。
here's what I mean let's say you know
我的意思是，假设
we're back 3,000 years right there's no
我们回到3000年前，那时还没有罐装配方奶粉，
formula in a can so women are
所以女性只能
breastfeeding their infants in order for
母乳喂养婴儿。为了让
that breast milk to come down and in in
乳汁分泌
order to be released to the infant
到婴儿体内，催产
oxytocin is really important oxytocin
素非常重要。催产素能让人平静
calms you down it relaxes you if you're
下来，放松身心。如果你
very tense and uptight milk isn't going
非常紧张焦虑，乳汁就根本无法
to come down at all so women have the
分泌。所以女性的
physiology in which to relax more easily
生理构造使她们更容易放松。
men on the other hand through Evolution
另一方面，从进化角度来看，男性一直
have been the protectors right so if
是保护者。所以，如果
there's a sabertooth tiger attacking a
有一只剑齿虎攻击
group of people who's going to jump up
一群人，谁会跳起来
and defend against that tiger well the
保护自己呢？
typically so men's bodies are really
通常是男性。男性的身体
built to stay vigilant and hypervigilant
构造使其能够保持警惕，
especially for attack well that attack
尤其是在面对攻击时。 这种攻击
doesn't have to be physical it can also
不一定是身体上的，它也可以
be mental emotional verbal and men will
是精神上的、情绪上的、言语上的。男性也会
have the same response we're talking
有同样的反应，我们这里说的就是“信息过载”，对吧？我们
concept talking about flooding yeah what
说的就是“信息过载”这个概念。
flooding John so flooding is really
约翰，什么是“信息过载”？“信息过载”实际上就是
going into fight or flight it's it's
进入“战斗或逃跑”的应激状态，也就是
when we start secreting cortisol and
我们开始分泌皮质醇和
adrenaline are two major stress hormones
肾上腺素——两种主要的压力激素。
and when we feel attacked when we feel
当我们感到受到攻击、感到
unsafe you know we start secreting these
不安全时，我们就会开始分泌这些
stress hormones and there are
压力激素。
of being physiologically flooded you
生理上的“信息过载”会带来一些心理上的影响，比如你
can't take in new information you rely
无法接收新信息，只能依赖过度
on overlearned habits it's like
学习的习惯。这就像一种
aggression or flight you know you you
攻击或逃跑的应激反应，
can't listen very well you actually your
你无法很好地倾听，你的
hearing is compromised your peripheral
听力和周边
vision is compromised you focus only on
视觉都会受到影响，你只会关注那些
the cues you need to survive the moment
能让你活下去的线索。
and so it's you you don't wind up being
所以，当你处于“信息过载”状态时，你最终不会成为一个
a very creative Problem Solver or a good
很有创造力的解决问题的人，也不会成为一个好的
listener when you're flooded if men
倾听者。如果男性
flood more than women does this go to
比女性更容易出现“信息过载”，这是否能
explain why men tend to avoid arguments
解释为什么男性
more than women cuz I think that's a
比女性更倾向于避免争论呢？因为我认为“
stereotype at least that men are much
男性
more avoidant in arguments I think I
更倾向于回避争论”至少是一种刻板印象。 在争吵中，我觉得
mean it's a stereotype that holds true
这是一种刻板印象，
to me I've never been sure whether it's
对我来说确实如此。我一直不确定这是
because we're not good at expressing our
因为我们不擅长表达自己的
emotions or if there's a physiological
情绪，还是因为
reaction in me that's making me go 80%
我体内存在某种生理反应，导致我80%的情况下都是
of the time women are the ones bringing
女性
up issues in a relationship now when
在恋爱关系中提出问题。当然，当
guys bring up the issues sometimes the
男性提出问题时，
women get flooded too so it's not that
女性有时也会情绪失控。所以并不是说
women don't get flooded you know yeah
女性不会情绪失控，
they're a little better at self soothing
她们确实比我们更擅长自我安抚。
than we are are but you know during
但是，你知道，在
during an argument if a woman gets
争吵中，如果一个女性情绪
flooded she really can't listen also and
失控，她就真的听不进去别人说话，而且
she repeats herself as well gets more
她还会重复自己的话，变得更加
strident you know if I'm flooded then
咄咄逼人。你知道，如果我情绪失控，
typical advice tells me John it says
通常的建议是，
never fall asleep if you and your
如果你和你的伴侣争吵了一段时间，千万不要睡着。那么，
something yeah what is the best I get
我有时也会情绪失控，
for me to deal with that if it's late at
如果到了深夜，我该如何应对呢？
night you should go to
你应该带着
sleep go to sleep angry I mean St Paul
怒气去睡觉。我的意思是，圣保罗
was the one who started that and he
是提出这个建议的人，而他当时还
wasn't married you know so it's you know
没有结婚。所以，你知道，
it sounds like great advice but if it's
这听起来是个很棒的建议，但是…… 如果这件事
going to keep you up and you know you're
会让你彻夜
going to get a terrible night's sleep
难眠，
you know shake hands and go to bed give
你知道自己今晚肯定睡不好，那就握手上床，
each other a quick kiss and go to bed
快速亲吻一下，然后带着
angry what did he start St Paul what did
怒气入睡。圣保罗说过什么？
St Paul start never go to bed wrathful I
圣保罗说过不要带着怒气入睡，我
think is what his advice was for couples
想这就是他对情侣的建议，
and that's wrong
但这不对。
yeah okay so if I if I'm in the middle
好吧，如果我正在
of an argument and I feel like I'm a
争吵，感觉有点情绪失控，手心都
a little bit sweaty I should take a time
出汗了，你应该
out is what you're saying Julie yeah
暂停一下，是吗，朱莉？是的，我们来
let's talk about that um so if you're
谈谈这个。如果你
feeling flooded um you really need to
感觉情绪失控，你真的需要休息一下，
take a break but there's specific steps
但休息是有具体步骤的。如果
one uh if you're flooded you say I need
你情绪失控，你应该说“我需要休息一下”，而不是说“我需要
to take a break you don't say you do I
休息一下”，然后说“我什么时候
come back to continue the
回来继续
conversation if you do that then your
谈话”。如果你这样做，你的
partner is not going to feel abandoned
伴侣就不会感到被抛弃
and rejected you go apart for maybe 30
和拒绝。你们可以分开30
minutes an hour however long maximum 24
分钟、1小时，或者更长时间，最多24
hours and you don't think about the
小时，期间不要想太多。
fight don't plan your
别在争吵前计划
rebuttal because that'll keep you
反驳，因为那样只会让你
flooded as long as you keep thinking
一直想着
about the fight so do something s
争吵的事。所以，去做些
soothing like reading a book reading a
舒缓的事情，比如读读书、看看
magazine working out maybe going for a
杂志、锻炼一下，或者去
run get on your computer get on your
跑步，打开
computer do your email don't watch
电脑看看邮件，别看
murder mysteries that's not a good thing
悬疑剧，那可不是什么好事。
to do so come back at the designated
等到约定的
time when hopefully your body is a lot
时间，希望那时你的身心已经
calmer and continue the
平静下来，再继续
conversation but you know a
对话。但你知道，一个
generally consistent result is that
普遍的结论是，
women tend to be more Unhappily Married
女性的婚姻往往比男性更不幸福。
guys often think everything's fine oh my
男人常常觉得一切都很好。我的
God so
天哪，这说得太对了！
true I actually had this conversation
我之前和前任有过类似的对话，
with a former partner where I said and I
我当时说了——我
shouldn't have said it but I just going
不该说的——但我还是要
to be honest I said to her in our
实话实说。我对她说，在我们的
relationship I think if you never raised
关系中，如果你从不提出
an issue I think there'd never be an
问题，我想就不会有
issue because I just felt like
问题了，因为我一直觉得
everything was always fine and every
一切都很好。但
week she was coming to me with a problem
她每周都会跟我抱怨问题，
and had she not come to me with that
如果她不跟我抱怨，
problem I think and I might be bsing
我想——我可能有点自欺欺人——我们的
myself here I think the relationship
关系会一直很
would have just been great right that's
完美，对吧？我当时就是这么想的。
how it felt and and you know women have
你知道，女人……
as well you know so I I think in a lot
你知道，女性比男性更容易患抑郁症。所以我觉得在很多
of ways the world is harder for women
方面，这个世界对女性来说更艰难，更
the world's a more dangerous place for
危险。
women for example the probability that a
例如，在美国，
woman will be physically or sexually
女性一生中遭受身体或性
assaulted in her lifetime is 40% it's 9%
侵犯的概率是40%，而男性只有9%。
from men in the United States I think
我认为做
it's harder to be a woman than it is to
女人比做
be a man I've sometimes rebutted myself
男人更难。朱莉，我有时也会反驳自己，
Julie when I talk when I say what I just
当我谈到
said about our relationship would be
我们之间的关系时，我说如果
fine if she never brought issues up
她从不提问题，那一切都会好起来。
because when I zoom out and I go the
因为当我跳出这个角度思考，她提出的那些问题是否让我们的关系
our relationship better and had she not
更好了？如果她没有提出这些问题，我们的关系会不会疏远？
and I say probably M see what I'm saying
我觉得很可能。你明白我的意思吗？
like I feel like my partner has always
我觉得我的伴侣一直在
played a role in keeping our
维系我们
relationship close the caretaker yeah
亲密的关系，扮演着照顾者的角色。是的，这是
yes is that a real thing yeah that
真的吗？是的，这
totally is a real thing what we saw in
绝对是真的。我们在
the research is that 80% of the time
研究中发现，80%的情况下，
women bring up the problems in a
女性会提出关系中的问题，
relationship 80% you know vast majority
80%，你知道，绝大多数。
and I think it's because again women you
我认为这是因为，你
know we talked about how men are raised
知道，我们之前讨论过男性……
in society well women are raised in
在社会中长大，女性被教育要养育子女，
society to nurture to create connection
建立
contion to maintain the family unit
联系，维护家庭，
right to create relationship and make
有权建立关系，并
sure the relationship is good and solid
确保关系良好、稳固
and secure so we were raised with
和安全。因此，我们从小就被灌输要对
relationship being good and when we
良好关系负责的观念。当我们
detect something isn't so good we're
发现关系出现问题时，我们会提出来。
causes a lot of the frustration is that
很多时候，我们感到沮丧，是因为
we we don't realize we don't have
我们没有意识到自己缺乏同理心，无法理解
empathy for how the other person is
对方在维系关系中所
playing a role in creating whole almost
扮演的角色。这几乎是
that make sense because I I understand
理所当然的，因为我明白，
as I said my relationship wouldn't be as
就像我之前说的，
good if my partner didn't bring up
如果我的伴侣不提出
issues but when she brings up issues I'm
问题，我们的关系就不会这么好。但当她提出问题时，我就会
like why are you bringing up issues you
想，你为什么要提出问题？你明白
know what I mean and it's that having
我的意思吗？这就是缺乏
that empathy sure but again um is she
同理心的问题。当然，但是，她
bringing up issues in a way that doesn't
提出问题的方式是否让人感觉是在
feel blaming or
责备或
critical to be honest to her she is
批评？说实话，
she's bringing them up pretty well great
她提出得相当不错，很好。
it's the way that I'm kind of
这就是我的
interpreting it yeah yeah I think much
理解。是的，我认为很多
of the problem well easy you know that
问题都出在这里。
happens easily to all of us because you
你知道，这种情况很容易发生在我们所有人身上。
know we've got these this baggage in our
我们每个人的过去都背负着一些包袱，这些包袱在
how we hear things how we perceive
我们听见和感知
things I have a hero on one of these
事物的方式上形成了某种过滤机制。我有一盘
videotapes there was a lawyer and this
录像带，里面有个我非常敬佩的人，他是一位律师。在
videotape he's helping his wife identify
录像带里，他帮助妻子找出他
what in his person personality really
性格中真正
makes her the most angry and he's
让她生气的地方。他问
helping her do that he's saying well is
她：“是不是因为我的说话
it is it the way I talk is that it and
方式？”
she says yeah it's the way you talk but
妻子回答说：“是的，就是你的说话方式。但是，
what what is it about the way you talk I
你说话的方式到底哪里有问题呢？我是说，是不是因为
mean is it what you know do I sound what
我听起来很
authoritarian or yes like the King has
专制，或者像国王
spoken and he says yeah well you know I
颁布法令一样？”律师说：“是的，你知道，
can I guess I am like that sometimes
我有时候就是这样，
works in the courtroom and she says well
在法庭上或许管用。”妻子说：“但这招
it doesn't work with me you know and he
对我不管用。”律师说：“嗯，这说得通。”
says well that makes sense he's my hero
他是我的偶像，
he just never gets defensive he's saying
他从不为自己辩解。他接着说：“跟
tell me more tell me more wow what a guy
我说说，跟我说说，哇，
Julie what do we misunderstand about
朱莉，你真是个了不起的人！”朱莉，我们对
conflict because you know I've come to
冲突的理解有什么误区吗？因为你知道，我逐渐
believe that the key to understanding if
意识到，
a relationship will be successful over
一段关系能否
the long term is how well the the pair
长久成功的关键在于双方如何
resolve conflict is that right wrong
解决冲突。是这样吗？对吗？显然，正如
well clearly uh as we said because 69%
我们所说…… 据说，69%
of all problems are Perpetual they are
的问题都是永久性的，它们永远
not going to be solved so if you rely on
无法解决。所以，如果你
seeing problems getting solved as an
把问题解决率作为衡量一段
relationship it's not going to look good
关系是否成功的指标，那看起来肯定不太妙。
right so you know what I think what we
你知道吗？我认为我们
need to understand about
需要理解的是，正如
conflict that we've written about in our
我们在
last book is that if we apply the dictum
上一本书中写到的，关于冲突，如果我们运用“先
of really understanding our partner and
真正理解伴侣及其
their point of view before before we
观点，然后再
work on trying to resolve the problem
着手解决问题”的原则，
we're going to do much
我们就能做得更好。
better conflict also gets a really bad
冲突本身也会造成非常糟糕的后果。
WP you know conflict you're not supposed
你知道，冲突不应该发生，
to have conflicts it means if you have a
这意味着如果一段
relationship with a lot of conflict that
关系中冲突不断，那就
means it's a bad relationship total myth
意味着这段关系很糟糕——这完全是无稽之谈，并非
that is not true what we've seen is that
事实。我们看到的是，那些确实会
couples who do fight but they fight
争吵的伴侣，如果他们像我们之前
right as we wrote about with the tools
写的那样，用
describing their own feelings and needs
描述自身感受和需求的方式去争吵，而不是
rather than blaming the partner then
指责对方，那么
they're going to really understand each
他们就能更好地理解
other so much better as the underlying
彼此。因为
dreams within the conflict come out the
冲突背后隐藏的梦想、
underlying family history comes out the
家庭背景、
life purpose comes out think about those
人生目标都会浮出水面。想想那些
conflict that if they are understood oh
冲突核心的重大问题，如果它们被理解，
my God you know so much more about your
天哪，你知道的。 比以前更了解你的
partner than you did before conflict how
伴侣，冲突之后，
do I become great at conflict and is
我该如何才能擅长处理冲突？
that really what I should be aiming at
这真的是我应该追求的目标吗？
should I be aiming at getting becoming a
我应该努力成为
master of conflict resolution I think so
冲突解决大​​师吗？我觉得，与其说是
you know it's not conflict resolution as
冲突解决，
much as it is conflict management and my
不如说是冲突管理。我的
secret is that notebook in my back
秘诀就是我后口袋里的笔记本。
pocket you know so I get it out you know
你知道，
when we have to talk about something
当我们不得不谈论重要的事情时，我会把它拿出来，认真倾听，然后记下来。
saying write it down is it in your
它现在在你
pocket now it's in my pocket now I'm
口袋里吗？现在在我口袋里。我正在
thinking of getting one here it is I'm
考虑也买一个。在这儿。我正在
thinking of getting one yeah it's really
考虑买一个。是的，它真的
great you know and so like if I say to
很好用。比如，如果我说
her she's upset you know or she wants to
她很生气，或者她想
talk about something important you know
谈谈重要的事情，我
I'm listening I'm taking notes so you
会认真倾听，并做笔记。
know and as I'm writing stuff down it
当我写下来的时候，我的心情会平静下来。
calms me down and I I'm writing it down
我一开始会
first first I'm saying why does she keep
想，为什么她总是
bringing up issues you know I didn't
提起这些问题？我不想这样度过
want to spend my evening this way but
我的夜晚。但
then I go oh that's a good point that's
后来我会想，哦，
that's interesting you know and I start
你说得对，这很有意思。然后我开始
realizing that she makes a lot of sense
意识到…… 她说的很有道理，这其中
is part of that moving the issue from
一部分原因在于，它把问题从
your amydala to your prefrontal cortex
你的杏仁核转移到了你的前额叶皮层，也就是说，
I.E it's moving it from your emotional
它把问题从你的情绪
Center to your logical Center yeah yeah
中心转移到了你的逻辑中心。是的，是的，
I really am CU that's that when you were
我真的很明白。你刚才
saying it I was like that would be you
说的时候，我就想，如果你
use the word it calms me down calms me
用“让我平静下来”这个词，
down that would help calm me down as
那确实能让我平静下来。是的，当然。
well yeah sure when you're taking notes
当你做笔记的时候，
you know it's more an intellectual
你知道，这更多的是一个理性的
process as opposed to an emotional
过程，而不是一个情绪化的
process right so it takes you out of
过程，对吧？所以它能让你摆脱被
what your partner is saying and into
伴侣的话语激起的情绪，转而专注于
just processing the words the language
处理文字，把它们
writing it down which keeps you calm I
写下来，这能让你保持冷静。有
one time I filled up an entire yellow
一次，我写满了一整本黄色
pad wow she said I want to talk to you
记事本。哇，她说：“我想和你谈谈，
and this I haven't talked to about this
这件事我从来没有跟你谈过，
ever and but I need you to really be
但我需要你
quiet and listen and I just kept writing
安静下来，认真听我说。”我就一直记着。
stuff down did he listen Julie when on
朱莉，他当时听了吗？
that occasion he really did it was
那一次他真的听了，真是
phenomenal and the wonderful thing that
太棒了。
you will discover if you take notes to
如果你也做笔记，你会发现一个很棒的好处，那就是它
is that it it makes your partner feel
会让你的伴侣感到自己被重视，感到自己很
valued feel important feel like whatever
重要，感到
they're saying is worth noting down
他们说的每句话都值得记录下来，对吧？ 这让我大吃一惊，
right it blew my mind I had no idea she
我完全不知道她
felt that those things it's important to
觉得那些事对
you it's important to you it's so
你来说很重要。 对你来说很重要，
important that you're going to take
重要到你要
notes on it my partner often says to me
记笔记。我的伴侣经常在争吵进行到一半时问我：“
you understand what I'm
你明白我说的意思吗？”
saying you know and she and I and that's
你知道，她和我……这其实是个
quite a curious question because I guess
挺奇怪的问题，因为我觉得
they're checking to see if yeah you've
她们是在确认你是否
heard and understood them which clearly
听到并理解了她们的话，这显然
is so important and that's a good way of
非常重要。这是一种很好的方式，
indicating that you do understand or at
表明你确实理解了，或者
least you're you know you're hearing and
至少你听到了并且
understanding mhm then you can say well
理解了。嗯，然后你可以说：“我
here's what I understand and then you
理解的是这样的。”你知道，有时候
know sometimes I'll do that Julie said
我会这么做。朱莉说：“
no that's not
不对，不是这样的。到底是什么？
it what what is it I thought I was
我以为我
hearing you oh you know and oh I missed
听到了。”哦，你知道，哦，我错过了。
that repair attempts you write about
修复尝试。你
repair attempts in your books what is a
在你的书中写到了修复尝试。约翰，什么是
repair attempt John you know here's the
修复尝试？你知道，
interesting thing is that most people
有趣的是，大多数人
don't repair very effectively the way an
修复争吵的效果并不好。
argument starts is the way it'll go 96%
争吵的开始方式，96%的情况下，就会一直这样发展下去。
% of the time so uh I had this woman
所以，我请了一位
named Nancy draus who came to my lab and
名叫南希·德劳斯的女士来我的实验室，
she had written a book of things you can
她写了一本书，讲的是
say when you're starting to get flooded
当你……时你可以说什么。 开始陷入
in an argument it was brilliant book
争吵的时候，我发现了一本很棒的书，
it's called talk to me like I'm someone
叫做《像爱人一样和我说话》，真的很
you love and it was really interesting
有意思。
but she had written these things down
作者是在非常冷静的情况下写下这些内容的，
when she was very calm and she wrote the
她就是
book that way but we actually went to
这样写的。但我们实际上去了
the lab and looked at how do couples
实验室，研究了情侣在
actually repair when they try to repair
试图修复关系时是如何做的。
and what we found was that any thing
我们发现，任何
that you would do in a business meeting
你在商务会议上会做的事情，
will fail in a love relationship let's
在恋爱关系中都会失败。让我们来
take a look at our options and evaluate
看看我们的选择，评估一下。我们的
them what are our priorities here what's
优先事项是什么？
our fundamental goal let's be rational
我们的根本目标是什么？让我们理性地看待这个问题。
let's evaluate the costs of one option
让我们理性地评估一下每个选择的成本。注定
doomed and the only thing that worked
失败。唯一有效的方法是
with somebody would say you know God you
说：“上帝，对不起，我
know I'm sorry I I said that you know
说了那样的话。
let let me try again or they would say
让我再试一次。”或者他们会说：“
you know um I'm really starting to feel
嗯，我真的开始感到很
defensive could you could you say that a
防备，你能用更
gentler way and those kinds of repairs
温和的方式说吗？”这些
that focused on emotion they worked and
专注于情感的修复方式是有效的，而且
the earlier they made them in the
在对话中越早使用，效果就越好。
were so these are attempts to repair the
所以，这些都是
relationship or the argument from one
从争吵的一方出发，试图修复关系或化解争吵的尝试。
side of the argument jul right yes in
是的，在
the middle of the conversation so if one
对话过程中，如果
one person senses it's getting off track
一方感觉谈话偏离了主题，
to get it back on track they may say one
为了回到正轨，他们可能会说
of these repair phrases but if the
一些修复短语。但如果
repair is going to be successful the
修复要成功，
other person has to accept the repair so
另一方必须接受。所以，
if John is saying to me hey I'm starting
如果约翰对我说：“嘿，我开始
to feel defensive can you say that you
感到有些防备，你能用更
know in a gentler
温和的
way I could either say no way forget it
方式说吗？”我可以选择说“不行，算了，你活该”，这等于
which is rejecting the repair or I could
拒绝修复；或者我可以
say ah you're right let me let me try
说“啊，你说得对，让我再试一次，
again and say it a different way that's
换个方式说”，这等于
accepting it but there's also repair
接受。但是，在一次
after an argument that has felt horrible
糟糕的争吵之后，也需要进行修复。
and then how do you process and repair
如何处理和修复
that terrible communication you had
你们之间糟糕的沟通呢？
that's a whole another that's what I was
这完全是另一回事。这就是我要说的。
to say of course it was here
当然，它就在这里，对吧？
right we're telepathic yeah so that
我们有心灵感应。所以，
coming back to it we have a method for
回到正题，我们有一种方法可以
doing that a five-step method for
做到这一点：一个五步法，用于在
relationship when you're calmer and and
冷静下来后重新审视关系中可能发生的令人后悔的事件。这个
that's very effective what is that fight
方法非常有效。是什么？
please give it to me yeah let me that
请告诉我。好的，让我来。
okay so it we actually have a little
所以，我们实际上有……
that a lot of people keep in their glove
很多人都会在
compartment because some for some reason
车里放一本小册子，里面把所有步骤都安排好了，因为有时候，不知为何，在
an hour down the freeway right never
高速公路上以每小时70英里的速度行驶时，争吵总是会发生，对吧？
fails so pull out the book okay in the
所以，拿出这本小册子。好的，小册子里的
booklet the first step is each person
第一步是，每个人都要
addresses a list of emotions that we've
面对我们打印出来的一系列情绪，
printed out and says out loud which
并大声说出自己
emotion they had during this regrettable
在这次令人遗憾的事件中感受到的情绪。
incident first of all and they can name
首先，他们可以列出尽可能
as many as they want and there are
多的
things like hurt angry abandoned
情绪，比如受伤、愤怒、被抛弃、被
rejected and so on secondly each person
拒绝等等。其次，每个人
has a chance to describe their point of
都有机会描述自己
view about what happened from beginning
对事件从头到尾的看法，
to end of this incident while the other
而另一个
person here we go again takes
人则要做好笔记。在一个
notes so at the end of the person's
人
narration they then summarize what they
叙述完毕后，另一个人要总结自己
heard that person say to make sure they
听到的内容，确保自己
got all the good points and then says
理解了所有要点，然后说
something validating like okay from your
一些肯定的话，比如：“好的，从你的
point of view I can see why you felt
角度来看，我能理解你为什么会有这种感觉。”
that way the way it's narrated is
叙述的方式
crucial it it sounds like I felt that
至关重要。听起来好像是：“我觉得
you were angry at me I saw this angry
你生我的气了。我看到你
look at your face I heard you say leave
脸上带着愤怒的表情。我听到你说‘别烦
me alone and get out of here I heard I
我，滚出去’。我听到，我
saw I felt mhm I
看到，我感觉到了……” 我
imagined so it's all about I it's not
设想，关键在于“我”，而不是
saying you said this mean thing to me
说你对我说过什么难听的话，这一点
which is critical all right so each
至关重要。每个
person has a chance to share their
人都有机会分享自己的
perception that way and their partner
感受，然后他们的伴侣
summarizes and validates what they heard
总结并确认他们听到的内容。
third people look at did I have any
第三步，人们会思考：我当时是否有任何
feelings during this that were actual
感觉是真正的
triggers that were feelings that got
触发因素？这些感觉可能
started long before this
早在这段
relationship in another relationship
关系之前就已存在，比如在另一段关系中，
maybe or even at home with my caretakers
甚至在家里和我的照护者
or my family if those feelings got
或家人相处时。如果这些感觉在此时此刻
triggered again here and now then you
再次被触发，那么你需要
share what feeling got triggered which
分享是什么感觉被触发了，
we call an enduring
我们称之为“持久的
vulnerability and say where it may have
脆弱性”，并说明它在
gotten started before this
这段
relationship that's step three step four
关系之前可能在哪里开始出现。这是第三步。第四步，
you're finally taking responsibility for
你最终要为
what you contributed to this regrettable
自己在这件令人遗憾的
incident by saying what was your state
事情中所扮演的角色承担责任，通过说明你当时的
of mind when it happened I was really
心理状态——比如“我
stressed I needed time alone you know
压力很大”、“我需要独处的时间”
Etc and then specifically saying what
等等——然后具体说明
you regret saying or doing during the
你在事件中说了或做了什么让你感到后悔，
incident and apologizing for it now note
并为此道歉。注意
how late the apology is coming you're
道歉的时间，你
not aping right away because that
没有立即道歉，因为那样
doesn't work you don't know what you're
行不通。
apologizing for if you haven't first
如果你没有先
heard the impact of that incident on
了解这件事对
your partner so step four is apologizing
你的伴侣造成的影响，你就不知道自己在为什么道歉。 第四步是道歉，
and then hopefully your partner accepts
然后希望你的伴侣能接受
your apology and finally step five is
你的道歉。最后，第五步是
saying one thing your partner can do
指出伴侣可以改变的一件事，以及
differently one thing you can do
你自己可以改变的一件事，
differently to avoid something like this
以避免类似的事情
from happening again then you're done
再次发生。这样就完成了
the repair attempts somewhat sounded
修复尝试。
like I was going to say backing down but
我刚才说的“退缩”听起来有点像是在说“退缩”，但其实更像是
you taking an objective view on the
你们其中一人客观地看待问题，然后
situation and kind of stepping outside
跳出来，
and saying I'm feeling like this it's
说“我感觉是这样”。这就像
almost like you're like stepping out of
你从
the video game grabbing the controller
电子游戏中抽身出来，拿起手柄，而不是继续玩下去。这样的
kind of like an accurate description I
描述准确吗？我
think so yeah yeah cuz sometimes that
觉得是的。因为有时候
does happen in my relationships where my
我的
partner will almost take a meta analysis
伴侣也会这样，他们会对情况进行一番“元分析”，然后说“我
go I'm not feeling this or I sorry
感觉不到这一点”或者“对不起，我……”。
uh I like take a meta approach they
他们
almost like step outside and give a
就像是跳出来，发表一番
commentary and that diffuses it I don't
评论，这样就化解了矛盾。“我
think you're listening to me something
觉得你没在听我说话”之类的。是的，他们必须
careful they shouldn't be number one
小心，他们不应该总是
analyzing you and where you're coming
分析你，揣测你的立场，也不应该
from and they shouldn't be blaming
指责你。
you're not listening to me shouldn't do
你没在听我说话，你不应该
that but if they say I'm not feeling
这样，但如果他们说我现在感觉没被
listened to right now yeah let me try
倾听，好吧，让我再试一次，
again yeah that's great interesting what
好吧，太好了，很有意思。那么
about sex and Intimacy in these subjects
性与亲密关系呢？在这些主题中，
what have you learned about the role of
你对
kissing in the love lab interesting yeah
接吻在爱情实验室中的作用有什么了解？很有意思。是的，
I mean you know we haven't done a lot of
你知道，我们对
research on sex we we did some in that
性方面的研究并不多，我们在那项
newlywed study cuz sex had gone down
新婚研究中做了一些，因为大多数夫妇的性生活都急剧减少，即使在
three years after the first baby was
第一个孩子出生三年后也是如此。
born and so we're asking people how did
所以我们询问人们是如何
they cope how did they keep sex alive
应对的，他们是如何保持性生活的。
but the biggest study done on this
但关于这个问题的最大规模的研究是
question was done uh in a book that came
在一本
out called the normal bar uh Christiano
名为《正常酒吧》（The Normal Bar）的书中完成的，克里斯蒂亚诺·
North is the first author of that and
诺斯是这本书的第一作者。
they analyze 70,000 people in 24
他们分析了24个国家的7万人，
countries and try to discern what's
试图找出那些
different about people who say they have
自称
a great sex life and people who say they
性生活美满的人和
have an awful sex life how are those two
那些自称性生活糟糕的人之间的区别。
groups of people different and they
他们
discovered that it was the same across
发现，这种情况在
the whole planet and and there are
全球范围内都是一样的，而且
really about a dozen things that people
人们
do have a great sex life and saying I
拥有美满性生活的原因大约有十几个。 每天都说“我
love you every day and meaning it is one
爱你”，并且真心实意地表达爱意，比如
of them giving
送
compliments uh romantic gifts having a
赞美、浪漫礼物、
lot of touch cuddling so of the people
多一些肢体接触和拥抱。在
who don't cuddle only 4% of them said
不拥抱的人中，只有4%的人表示
they had a great sex life 96% of the
他们的性生活很美满，96%的
non- cuddlers had an awful sex life so
人性生活很糟糕。所以
touch is very important important even
肢体接触非常重要，即使是
physical touch even in public affection
身体接触，甚至在公共场合表达爱意也很重要。
in public was a big thing and really you
你
know that kind of connection the
知道，那种
romantic date you know the Romantic
亲密的联结，比如浪漫的约会、浪漫的假期，
vacation that's what they did so nothing
他们就是这么做的。这里没有
involved kissing or what happened in the
提到接吻，也没有提到卧室里发生的事情。
bedroom so none of that is there but
但是，
there has been research on just kissing
关于接吻的研究已经表明，
and it turns out that not every culture
并非所有文化中都有
do humans kiss but in the ones they do
接吻的习俗，但在有
kiss is very powerful very erotic for
接吻的文化中，接吻对大多数情侣来说都非常强烈、非常性感，
most most couples and it's a nice
而且是通往
Gateway into eroticism I found this
情欲的美好途径。我发现一项
really interesting study um in your work
非常有趣的研究，在你的作品中提到了
where it said a 10-year German study
一项为期10年的德国研究，该研究
that found that right said again you can
发现，那些在
leave for work live something like four
上班前亲吻妻子道别的男性比那些
years longer than men who don't so and
不这样做的男性寿命长约四年。 所以，
that's a Priory kiss you know don't
这就是普赖尔之吻，你知道，
forget Sten they're getting mured being
别忘了斯滕，他们正在被“
muted but the sixc kiss which we
谋杀”（mure，指被静音），但我们推荐的六秒之吻
recommend has much more potential than
比
that pick on the she cheek what is the
那种亲吻脸颊更有潜力。什么是
sixc kiss a kiss that lasts at least six
六秒之吻？就是持续至少
seconds why not five or four because uh
六秒的吻，为什么不是五秒或四秒？因为，呃，
oxytocin gets secreted with a 20 second
催产素会在一次20秒的
hug or a 6C kiss you're both secreting
拥抱或六秒之吻中分泌，你们双方都会分泌
oxytocin and that creates a sense of
催产素，这会创造一种
psychological safety and connection and
心理安全感、联结感
bonding and bonding what what do you
和亲密感。
think about the subject of um sex Julie
朱莉，你对性这个话题怎么看？
and you know how important it is for a
你知道它对一段关系
relationship how much should we be
有多重要，我们应该多久做一次
having sex does it really matter is it a
爱？这真的重要吗？它能
predictor of long-term success in
预测婚姻的长期成功吗？
marriage great questions um that my
很好的问题，我的
clients ask me a lot and there's huge
客户经常问我。
variability in sexual preference some
性偏好差异很大，有些
couples actually don't want to have sex
夫妻根本不想做爱，
at all both people don't want to have
双方都不想，
sex they'd rather have kind of a sibling
他们宁愿拥有类似兄妹般的亲密
relationship ship almost if they're both
关系。如果他们都对此感到
content with that then they can have a
满意，那么他们就能拥有
very successful relationship some
非常成功的关系。有些
couples really want to have sex a lot
夫妻真的很想经常做爱，
you know all the time and it's a really
你知道，所有这些…… 时间是维系关系
important component of the
中非常重要的组成部分，
relationship uh and everything in
而
between when you run into trouble is the
当你们遇到问题时，通常会出现
following and I've seen this so many
以下情况。我见过太多这样的例子：那些
times the men who I guess I would say
我称之为“
are hyper master Uline they think that
过度依赖”的男人，他们认为
cuddling is too infantile so they don't
拥抱太幼稚，所以他们
want to cuddle and the only way they can
不想拥抱。他们唯一能
accept physical contact which they
接受身体接触的方式，也是他们
desperately need is through sex period
迫切需要的，就是性交，
right and the woman has 17 children
没错，就是插入式性交。而女人有17个孩子，
she's trying to make dinner you know
她还要做饭，你知道
she's
她
exhausted um she may not want to have
很累，她可能不像
sex near nearly as much as he does so he
男人那样渴望性爱。所以他
begins to feel deprived of touch but
开始感到缺乏触碰，但
instead of complaining about that he
他并没有抱怨，而是
says we're not having enough
说我们
sex and she says I'm not getting enough
性生活不够，而她则说我得不到足够的
affection and there you have you know
爱抚。于是，
some conflict that has to get sorted out
冲突就出现了，需要解决。
it's like they're speaking two different
他们就像在说两种不同的
languages of intimacy you what I mean
亲密语言。我的意思是，从某种意义上说，
basically in a sense they are they are
他们的确如此。
though typically the in these
通常情况下，在这样的
relationships really basically need
关系中，他们真的非常需要
touch and can they accept cuddling as
触碰，但他们能接受拥抱这种同样重要的
something that's just as masculine as
东西吗？ 男性性行为，比如
penetrative sex
插入式性行为，
well if they really think about it and
如果他们真的认真思考并
if they experience it then yeah you C
亲身体验过，那么是的，你可以理解，
they can then things really will tend to
事情真的会朝着好的方向发展。
improve the research there John is
约翰也
suggesting though as you said that life
提出了类似的研究，正如你所说，生活本身
is foreplay because if like the the
就是前戏。如果
kissing on the way out the door and the
出门前的亲吻、
touching my partner's back and the
抚摸伴侣的背、
cuddle leads to a better sex life then
拥抱等行为能够改善性生活，那么
we should see life public displays of
我们应该把生活中公开示爱等等都看作是对
investment in what happens tonight in
今晚卧室里发生的事情的一种投资。
the bedroom right I think that's really
我认为这确实如此。
true every positive thing you do in a
你在一段关系中做的每一件积极的事情
relationship is foreplay and the couples
都是前戏。
who a lot of times the couples who stop
很多时候，那些停止
having sex have also shut down high
性生活的伴侣，尤其是那些冲突不断的伴侣，他们也关闭了
other things other sensual parts of
其他方面，关闭了生活中其他感官享受的部分。
their lives as well you know they're not
你知道，他们不再
having much fun and you know 80% of the
享受性爱的乐趣。在
40,000 couples we studied said that fun
我们研究的4万对伴侣中，有80%的人表示，他们的
had come to die in the relationship
关系中乐趣已经消失
there was much play there wasn't much
殆尽。他们不再像以前那样玩乐，而是充满了
Adventure it wasn't just sex everything
冒险，不仅仅是性爱，
shut down all the things that were
所有那些
really delightful you know exploring new
真正令人愉悦的事情都被关闭了，比如探索新的性爱方式。
kinds of Cuisine you know traveling
你知道，美食、旅行、
uh playing games together you know
一起玩游戏、
playing sports together how do we stop
一起运动……我们该如何阻止
that happening though you know because
这种情况发生呢？因为
I've often wondered people often said to
我经常思考，人们常跟
me that eroticism and attraction is
我说，情欲和吸引力
about novelty and spontaneousness and
在于新鲜感和自发性，以及
doing all that kind of thing and then
做所有这些事情；然后
they've said that love is about
他们又说，爱情在于
familiarity and you know Comfort which
熟悉和舒适，你知道，这
are these are two opposite things let me
两者是截然相反的。让我来
answer that the person who said that
回答一下：那些说
it's all about spontaneity and mystery
一切都关乎自发性和神秘感
at so on has never done any research the
等等的人，从未做过任何研究。
research shows that the
研究表明，
familiarity the emotional connection
熟悉感，也就是情感上的联结，
really knowing your partner creates in
真正了解你的伴侣，从
the long run much more passion what much
长远来看，会创造出更多的激情，
better sex actually than maintaining
实际上，这比保持
mystery but not really connecting to one
神秘感却不真正建立彼此联结的性爱要好得多。
wonderful book by Emily ngosi called
艾米丽·恩戈西写了一本很棒的书，叫做《
come as you are that reviews This
来吧，做你自己》，书中回顾了这项
research and it shows that first of all
研究，并指出，首先，
women have more prerequisites for
女性对
eroticism than men do Jeffy Chase once
情欲的先决条件比男性更多。杰菲·蔡斯曾经
said women need a reason for sex men
说过，女性需要性爱的理由，而男性只
need a place that's all so you know but
需要一个地点，仅此而已。所以你知道，但这
it's true
是真的，
men men don't need to feel safe to feel
男性不需要感到安全才能产生
sexual women do women need to feel
性欲，而女性则需要感到
psychologically safe and that means
心理上的安全感。 安全感意味着
emotional connection it also means there
情感上的联结，也意味着
can't be a long to-do list of things
不能有一大堆待办事项被忽略——比如遛狗、上厕所等等。这样，
erotic to a woman and she's receptive
女性才会感到情欲涌动，并且乐于接受。
let me point out something in addition
此外，我还想指出一点，
to that that most men don't know at
大多数男性并不了解：
least in the United States one out of
至少在美国，
four women have been sexually molested
四分之一的女性在18岁之前遭受过性骚扰
or sexually assaulted by the age of
或性侵犯，而
18 and that's only the women who report
这仅仅是那些报案的女性。如果算上那些没有报案的女性，
it it's probably one out of three maybe
可能高达三分之一，甚至
40% including the ones who haven't
40%。
reported it so when women have that
所以，当女性有这样的
history not not to mention thousands of
经历，更不用说她们几千年来一直被
years in their bones of being seen only
视为
as sex objects and being raped you know
性对象，几乎每天都遭受强奸时，
day you get to understand why women need
你就能理解为什么女性
safety much more so than men yeah we
比男性更需要安全感。是的，我们
wrote a book called The Man's Guide to
写了一本书，叫做《男人的
women to convey all of these bits of
女性指南》，旨在传达所有这些
information that have been researched so
经过研究的信息。
familiarity is the basis for AIC
熟悉程度才是AIC的基础，而
not for the absence of a rism that's a
不是不存在风险——那只是个
myth so I've heard a lot about
神话。 我最近听说了很多关于表观
epigenetics recently which is this idea
遗传学的东西，它指的是
that trauma can be passed on from one
创伤可以代代相传。
in mind if women have been sort of sex
考虑到这一点，如果女性
objects throughout history and have been
在历史上一直被物化为性对象，遭受
raped and those kinds of things it's
强奸等等，那么
understandable that as you say Julie
正如你所说，朱莉，
that they have like an inbuilt need for
她们天生就需要
safety that men might not understand in
安全感，而男性可能并不完全理解这一点。这对男性来说意味着什么呢？
do you then give to a man is is the
你给男性的建议是什么？是
advice you have to make your partner
让伴侣
feel safe for them to be aroused or to
感到安全，这样他们才能被唤起性欲吗？对了，
okay yes what else was in that book by
那本书里还有什么其他内容？顺便说一句，那
the way it's quite an interesting book I
本书很有意思，我
feel like I need to read it yeah it's
觉得我应该读一读。嗯，
well you know it's really that awareness
你知道，这本书真正强调的是
of emotional connection and
情感联结和
psychological safety being so important
心理安全
to women and also realizing that men who
对女性的重要性，以及意识到
do housework get a lot more
做家务的男性性
sex is that something Julie told you or
生活更频繁。朱莉是告诉你的吗？还是说，
is that no that is it's actually an
这实际上是一个
empirical result yeah but specifically
经验结果？是的，具体来说，
honey they have to do the vacuum in yeah
他们得吸尘，还得把
and get the books off the
床上的书拿走。很
bed interesting okay are you seeing a
有意思。你觉得
difference in our relationship with sex
我们与性的关系有什么变化吗？
um as the world is changing because
嗯，就像这个世界一样。 情况正在发生变化，因为
there's some stats that suggest we're
一些统计数据表明，
getting more and more sexless as a as a
作为一个社会，我们的性生活越来越少。在
your 50 years studying love towards
你研究爱情的50年里，你是否观察到人们对
attitudes about sex or you know gender
性的态度发生了任何变化？你知道，性别
roles have changed in that time as well
角色在这段时间里也发生了变化。
in society so you know I wouldn't say
所以，我不会说现在是
it's sexless but I would say it's
无性社会，但我会说是无
Loveless more Loveless in the sense uh
爱社会，更确切地说是无爱社会。
you know again I don't know what it's
你知道，我不太了解
like in England or in other countries so
英国或其他国家的情况，
much but in the United States the hookup
但在美国，约炮
culture is a is you know alive and
文化依然
thriving there's so many websites in
盛行。有很多网站，
which um men and men women and women men
男男、女女、
and women are just hooking up meaning
男女都在约炮，也就是
meeting up for the first time having sex
第一次见面就发生性关系，然后就
and departing the end is that a
离开。这有
problem yes you know why because in that
问题吗？是的，你知道为什么吗？因为在这种
kind of sex there's no emotional
性关系中，没有任何情感
connection zero and I've heard this from
联系，一点都没有。事实上，我从
both men and women actually that when
男人和女人那里都听到过这种说法：他们
they leave they feel more empty than
离开后感觉比
before they started having that sex what
发生性关系之前更空虚。
do you think that is no emotional
你觉得这是为什么？因为没有情感
connection it's impersonal sex they
联系，这是非人格化的性行为，他们
don't know who they're having sex with
不知道自己和谁发生了性关系。
so you know it's almost like
这几乎就像
masturbating practically so you know
自慰一样，你知道，
there's a lot of couples who are doing
很多情侣都在
that but they're they're not committing
这样做，但他们不像以前那样愿意
in long-term relationships as much as
投入长期的恋爱关系。
they used to and I think there's several
我认为这其中有几个
factors involved in that one is they've
因素：首先，他们
seen their parents divorce so they don't
目睹了父母离婚，所以他们不
believe in marriage or commitment as an
相信婚姻或承诺这种
institution that they should live
制度，不认为这是他们应该为之奋斗的；
to um secondly women have come into the
其次，
workforce again in the last 50 years and
过去50年里，女性重新进入职场，
career is equally important to many
事业对很多
women as it is to
女性来说和
Men on that point do you see issues with
男性一样重要。关于这一点，你认为
women becoming more successful in that
女性越来越成功是否会在
emasculating men to some degree because
某种程度上削弱男性的男子气概？因为
I read about a study that um said
我读过一项研究，指出
there's an expectation in society for
社会期望
men to provide more at home financially
男性在经济上承担更多责任；另
and then a separate study showed that um
一项研究表明，
women and it women's sort of equality
女性
with men in terms of their pay and
在薪酬和教育方面与男性的平等程度
education has is getting closer and then
正在提高；
the third study says that men can feel
第三项研究则指出，男性
emasculated in the presence of a smarter
在更聪明、
more successful women and they find it
更成功的女性面前会感到自尊心受损，觉得她们
less attractive so if you put all this
没那么有吸引力。所以，如果你把所有这些因素
together and you go okay women are
综合起来，再加上女性越来越
getting richer and more intelligent um
富有、越来越聪明……
men are emasculated by that but men
男人因此感到自卑，但他们
still have this ex social expectation
仍然抱有这种社会期望，认为
that they'll pay the bill in that
他们应该承担经济责任。在这种情况下，
for you know and you can look at it
你会想：我的天哪，这太难了。你可以
another way and say there's less of a
换个角度来看，现在
pool for women who typically want to
女性的选择范围越来越小，她们通常希望和
date men that have a certain level of
拥有一定
education and a certain level of money
教育水平和经济实力的男性约会，这个群体比以往任何时候都
the pool is smaller than ever before so
小。所以，
is this you know this some of the issues
这算是现代社会的一些问题和
of the the mo some of the challenges of
挑战吗？
the modern world you're right yeah
你说得对，
you're absolutely right about that the
你说的完全正确。
roles are really changing and um you
角色真的在发生变化。嗯，
know I remember this feeling myself
我记得我自己也有过这种感觉。在
actually as I built my career and John
我事业起步的时候，
and I were together and I kept thinking
我和约翰在一起，我一直在想：
no no no I should be a housewife I
不，不，不，我应该做个家庭主妇，我应该
should just be a mom I should just be
只做个妈妈，我应该只
taking care of the home I shouldn't be
照顾家庭，我不应该把
devoting all this time to my career but
所有时间都投入到事业中。但
I love my career I want to work and so
我热爱我的事业，我想工作。所以，我内心一直很
there would be this turmoil inside about
纠结，我应该成为什么样的人。
who should I be and I think men are
我认为男人也有这种
feeling that too for example as I said
感觉。例如，就像我
earlier men are really wanting to be
之前说的，男人越来越渴望成为
fathers more but how can you be an
父亲，但怎样才能成为一个
involved father when you're working like
尽职尽责的父亲呢？ 当你
crazy extra overtime to make more money
拼命加班挣更多钱的时候，
right it's impossible also those old
这根本不可能。而且，那些根深蒂固的
myths have a hard time falling away that
观念也很难改变，比如
men who make more money have more status
男人挣得多就更有地位，更
have more value as human beings are
有价值，是
better Partners that's so more male are
更好的伴侣。这种说法完全是
more male are more masculine it's so not
错误的。还有
true another thing to keep in mind is
一点需要记住，过去女性的
dollar that men made now they make 81
收入只有男性的79%，现在女性的收入是男性的81%。
cents for every dollar you think that's
你觉得这
a big change it is not so women are
变化很大吗？其实不然。女性仍在为
career opportunities work opportunities
职业机会、工作机会等方面的平等而奋斗，她们也仍在
and so on and valuing their
重视自己的
career
事业。
men sometimes you know are struggling
男性有时会感到迷茫，不知道自己该何去何从。
who should I be now I used to be the
我以前是家里的顶梁柱，现在我该如何是好？
provider who should I be well that's
这就是我们从小到大学到的，
what we've learned right cuz we come
因为我们这一代人，
from a generation where like my father
比如我父亲那一代……
might have been the provider and my
我
granddad was the provider so I've
祖父可能是家里的顶梁柱，所以我以他为榜样，心想，要想
modeled that and said well for me to be
成为像
a man like my father and I need to be
我父亲那样的男人，我必须能够承担起
able to do this but that's right that's
这个责任。当然，
right it's a good thing that we're
我们正在逐步实现平等，这当然是件好事。
I know the pay Gap is still there's
我知道男女薪酬差距依然存在，
still a distance there between men and
男女之间仍然存在隔阂。
women but it it kind of you can see
但你也能看出，
men who now don't know their role but
现在很多男性面临着挑战，他们不清楚自己的角色，但
Society still has an expectation that
社会仍然期望
they'll pick up the bill you bet it's a
他们承担经济责任。这的确是个
difficult conundrum isn't it but it's
难题，不是吗？这对
well it's really hard on men you know I
男性来说真的很难。我
think men in many ways are having as
认为，在很多方面，男性
hard if not harder time now in figuring
现在在
out what their role is and who they want
弄清楚自己的角色和想要
to be compared with women I mean our
成为什么样的人方面，面临的困难不亚于女性，甚至可能更大。我的意思是，我们的
fight started earlier Right started in
斗争开始得更早，早在
the 70s with women's Liberation and Men
70年代的妇女解放运动时期就开始了。当时男性却
kind of sat back and went what what's
袖手旁观，不知所措。
happening I think I think men are
我认为，男性正在逐渐
discovering the importance of
意识到
relationships you know uh we typically
人际关系的重要性。我们通常
have had worse emotional support systems
情感方面的问题更严重。
you know uh many men don't don't have a
你知道，很多男人没有
best friend don't have close friends and
知心好友，没有亲密的朋友，
their only con really close connection
他们唯一真正亲密的联系
is with the woman that they live with
就是和同居
and or married to and so I think men are
或已婚的女人。所以我认为，男人正在逐渐
discovering how important social
意识到，社交
connection is in their lives compareed
关系在他们的生活中比事业成就更重要。
to achievement you know I mean there's
你知道，一直以来，
got sold to women that if they really
女性都被灌输了一种谎言：如果她们是维系
are the caretakers of relationships
感情的付出者，
they'll be happy the lie to men is if
她们就会幸福；而男性则被灌输了一种谎言：
you are successful in your career you'll
事业成功就会
be happy neither neither lie is really
幸福。这两种谎言都没什么
useful because both men and women need
用，因为男人和女人都需要
close connections they need we need
亲密的联系，都需要
friends we need you know there's an
朋友，都需要……
epidemic of loneliness you know in the
你知道，现在世界上孤独成灾，
world right now and that's a killer we
这简直是致命的。我们
really need to reach out more not only
真的需要更多地与人交往，不仅要
to make good friends but also reach out
结交好朋友，还要主动接触
to strangers create community and that
陌生人，建立社群。这种情况
needs to change you know what's really
必须改变。你知道吗？真正
interesting I mean just think about it
有趣的是，想想看，
if you go on the internet and you look
如果你上网看看
at what women are looking for in a
女性在寻找什么样的
partner what's the first word they say
伴侣，她们说的第一个词是什么？
they don't say rich they don't say
她们不会说富有，也不会说
highly successful great
非常成功、成就斐然，
achievements typically they say
她们通常会说
sensitive right sensitive emotionally
敏感，对吧？情感上很敏感。
aware
有意识地
caring so hopefully men can absorb that
关心他人，希望男性能够理解这一点。
is that it's interesting because they do
这很有意思，因为他们确实会
say that yeah and then they also say
这么说，然后他们又会说自己很
strong and they say um can protect me
强壮，说自己能保护自己。
and and again it feels like a pole
这感觉就像一个两极，
because on one end it appears that that
因为一方面，这种
sort of sensitive emotional openness at
敏感的情感开放，
somewhat sensing contrast to like
某种程度上与……形成对比，就像……嗯，
the it's like how do I very well you
你
have a very lucky part those people
很幸运，那些
probably listening don't even know what
听众可能根本不知道
I did but I was just flexing my guns it
我做了什么，但我只是在炫耀我的肌肉，那是个
was the gun show so like you see what
肌肉秀。所以你明白
I'm saying it feels like a contradiction
我的意思，这感觉像是一个矛盾，就像
it's like how you be the this and this
你既是这样的，又是那样
the testosterone filled beasts that's
充满睾酮的野兽，可以
going to save the day and then the true
拯救世界，然后是真的。
but keep in mind that being strong
但请记住，坚强
doesn't mean being
并不意味着冷漠。
unemotional sometimes it takes more
有时候，
strength and courage to voice emotion
表达情感比压抑情感需要更大的力量和勇气。
they're talking about you know let's not
她们在谈论什么？
forget that women are still getting
别忘了，女性仍然会遭受
raped still getting assaulted still
强奸、性侵犯、到处遭受
getting attacked everywhere still
攻击、
getting murdered right so they want a
被谋杀，对吧？所以她们想要一个
man allegedly who can physically protect
据说能在身体上保护
them for sure that would feel great
她们的男人，这当然会感觉很好，
because women still feel
因为女性仍然感到
unsafe
不安全。
however that doesn't necessarily
然而…… 这并不一定
correlate with being
意味着
unemotional I guess the contradiction
冷漠无情。我想这种矛盾
goes both ways because men also want a
是双向的，因为男人也想要一个
woman that is you know compassionate and
温柔体贴的女人，
soft but they also wanted to just be
但他们也希望女人
like to not not be emotional and not
不要那么情绪化，不要那么拘泥于情感。
keep that so it's like a contradiction
所以这就像一个双向的矛盾。是啊，是啊，
both ways yeah yeah yeah we want
我们都想要
everything right all at once and that's
一切都完美，而这正是
part of the problem just closing off on
问题的一部分。
this point about sex cuz I had one last
关于性，我就先说到这里吧，因为我还有一个
question which is does the research show
问题：研究表明，
that couples that have the best sex life
性生活最美的伴侣是否也
talk about it the most yes I had this
最常谈论性？是的，我
debate with my friend and I was
和朋友讨论过这个问题，我想知道答案。是的，
wondering yes no question coupl who talk
毫无疑问，谈论
about it have a better sex life and how
性生活的伴侣性生活更美满。那么
should they be talking about it give me
他们应该如何谈论性呢？请给我
some advice on how to talk about sex
一些建议，告诉我该如何
with my partner you need to talk about
与伴侣谈论性。你需要
it in a way that is uh accepting and
以一种接纳和
loving you know so you talk about what's
爱的方式来谈论性。所以，你可以谈谈这段
really great in the relationship what
关系中真正美好的地方，
you've enjoyed what you love about your
你享受过的事情，你爱
partner what you find sexy about your
伴侣的哪些方面，你觉得
partner what you wish for more of you
伴侣性感的地方，以及你希望拥有更多什么。对了，
know and right we have we created what
我们创造了
we call got
我们称之为“
sex it's isn't that a I we didn't think
性爱”的东西，这难道不是一个……我们没想到
of the title I promise so it's it's a
这个名字吗？ 承诺，这是一个
kit that includes seven different uh
包含七个不同结构化对话的工具包，供你和
your partner about sex
伴侣就性进行对话，内容
that have to do with what do you prefer
涉及你具体喜欢什么，比如
specifically uh how would you like sex
你希望性爱如何
to be initiated when would you like it
开始，何时
initiated how can we refuse sex without
开始，我们如何在不
massacring each other's
伤害彼此
egos how should sex be completed Etc so
自尊的情况下拒绝性爱，性爱应该如何结束等等。因此，那些更
the couples who talk much more openly
开放、
and more comfortably about that do much
更自在地谈论这些话题的伴侣，在
better sexually and for love Maps we
性生活和爱情方面都表现得更好。我们
have 100 questions you can ask a man
有100个问题，你可以问男人
about his erotic world and 100 questions
关于他的性幻想世界的问题，也有100个问题，
you can ask a woman about her erotic
你可以问女人关于她的性幻想
world and they're not the same questions
世界的问题。男女的问题并不相同，因为
generally even in sort of homosexual
即使在同性恋
relationships and heterosexual
关系和异性恋
relationships have very different
关系中，人们的性
fantasies yeah often linked to their
幻想也往往截然不同，这通常与他们的
trauma where wherever they come from
创伤经历有关，无论他们来自哪里，无论他们来自哪里。
when one partner isn't willing to do the
当伴侣中的一方不愿意满足
fantasy that the other partner is really
另一方真正
craving how how does one navigate that
渴望的性幻想时，该如何应对呢？有
well couple of ways one is the person
两种方法：一是
who's not willing to do it can maybe
不愿意满足幻想的一方可以尝试用
describe it verbally because couples who
语言描述，因为那些更愿意
talk more during sex actually have
沟通的伴侣更容易做到这一点。 在性爱过程中，
better sexual relationships too so if
如果
the partner who doesn't want to do what
一方不想做
the other wants at least describes it
另一方想做的事，至少能用
verbally Whispering it in some kind of
一种
really cool tone well the guy can get
很酷的语气低声描述出来，那么男性
off on that or the woman can get off on
或女性都能从中获得快感。
that right I'm imagining you're a
我猜你
cheerleader right now and I'm the
现在是啦啦队员，我是
football
橄榄球
player and I'm 6'4 not 5 foot s for all
运动员，而且我身高6英尺4英寸（约1.93米），不是5英尺（约1.52米）。对于所有正在收听的
the businesses and entrepreneurs out
商家和企业家来说，
there listening if I asked you which
如果我问你们哪个
platform you think gives you the highest
平台的
return for your paid ads what do you
付费广告回报率最高，
think you'd say the answer might
你们会怎么回答？答案可能会让
surprise you and that is LinkedIn ads
你们惊讶，那就是LinkedIn广告。
who I'm happy to say are now a sponsor
我很高兴地告诉大家，LinkedIn现在是本
of this podcast reaching the right
播客的赞助商。触达合适的
customers and clients can be complex and
客户可能很复杂，
trust me I know all about the struggles
相信我，我深知其中的挑战。LinkedIn
of doing that LinkedIn ads makes the
广告让这个
process super easy and empowers
过程变得超级简单，并为
marketeers with solutions that fit you
营销人员提供符合您、您的
your business needs and your customers
业务需求和客户需求的解决方案。
you'll be able to drive results with
您可以使用专为B2B营销
targeting and measurement tools built
打造的定位和衡量工具来推动业绩增长。
marketing in fact 79% of B2B content
事实上，79%的B2B内容
marketers said that LinkedIn produces
营销人员表示，LinkedIn在
the best results for paid media and
付费媒体方面效果最佳。
that's because you'll have direct access
那是因为您将直接接触
to a billion members 70 million decision
到十亿会员、七千万
makers and 10 million C Level Executives
决策者和一千万C级高管。
I highly recommend you check it out I'm
我强烈建议您了解一下。我将为
giving the doac community a $100 credit
DOAC社区提供100美元的
for your first LinkedIn campaign just
LinkedIn推广额度，只需
head to linkedin.com
访问linkedin.com/doac/24即可立即
doac 24 to get started right now let's
开始。接下来我们来
talk about Zoe who you may know because
聊聊Zoe，您可能听说过，因为
they're a sponsor of this podcast and
他们是本播客的赞助商，而
I'm an investor in the company you guys
我也是该公司的投资人。大家都
know health is my number one priority
知道，健康是我的首要任务。Zoe
Zoe's growth story has been absolutely
的发展历程令人
incredible so far they're doing science
难以置信。到目前为止，他们正在以
at a scale that I've never seen before
前所未有的规模开展科学研究。
because of their members and recent
得益于他们的会员、近期的
breakthroughs and research they can now
突破和研究，他们现在可以
continue to offer the most
继续提供市面上最
scientifically Advanced gut health test
先进的肠道健康检测。
on the market previously the test
此前，该检测
allowed them to analyze 30 bacteria
可以分析
types in your gut but now thanks to new
您肠道中的30种细菌，但现在，得益于新的
science they've identified 100 bacteria
科学技术，他们已经识别出100
types this is a huge step forward and
种细菌。这是一个巨大的进步，目前
even close to it on the market at all so
市面上没有任何其他产品可以与之媲美。
to find out more and to get started on
要了解更多信息并开启
your Zoe Journey visit zoe.com
您的Zoe之旅，请访问zoe.com/stepen。
stepen you can use my exclusive code
您可以使用 我的专属折扣码
ceo1 for 10% off don't tell anybody
ceo1 可享 10% 折扣，别告诉别人哦，
about that okay just for you guys the
好吗？就给你们这些“
love lab Research indicates that
爱情实验室”的朋友们。研究表明，
betrayal lies at the heart of every
背叛是每段
failed relationship this was in your
失败关系的根源。这在你的
book the seven principles of of making
书《让婚姻成功的七项原则》里也有提到。背叛有很多种
of ways to really betray a partner in a
方式，
relationship I mean you know cheating is
我的意思是，你知道，出轨是
one way but any kind of betrayal is
一种，但任何形式的背叛都
something that needs to be healed in a
需要在关系中得到修复。
relationship for example if you've uh
例如，如果你和
teamed up with somebody in your family
家人联手
against your partner uh at some point
对抗你的伴侣，在某种程度上，
that may feel like a betrayal um you
这可能会让你感觉像是一种背叛。你
know and it doesn't have to be sexual
知道，这种背叛不一定是性方面的，
but it's something that needs to be
但它需要被
healed because trust and commitment are
修复，因为信任和承诺是
so important as the Bedrock of every
每段关系的基石，非常重要。
relationship if I was to say tell me the
如果我问你，
exact you know in your love lab two c a
在你的“爱情实验室”里，一对
couple walk in and they they're there
情侣走进来，他们要在那里待
for 24 hours in your love lab and you're
24 小时，你要
studying them can you
观察他们。你能
roleplay the behavior that a couple who
模拟一对
are destined to fail would exhibit oh
注定失败的情侣会表现出的行为吗？哦，当然
yes how many ways can we do that okay
可以，有多少种方式？ 好的，我们做吧。
God these crossover puals are really
天哪，这些交叉填字游戏真的
hard
很难。
H you know I'm really sick and tired of
你知道吗，我真的受够了
you always paying attention to your
你总是关注你那些
stupid crossw word puzzles they're just
愚蠢的填字游戏，它们简直是在
they're such a waste of time I don't
浪费时间。我不
know why you do that it's it's just
知道你为什么这么做，这
stupid yeah well I I I think they're too
太蠢了。是啊，我觉得它们
challenging for you
对你的
intellectually that's why you avoid them
智力来说太有挑战性了，所以你才逃避它们。
what are you talking about I could do
你在说什么？我
that with almost my eyes CL I never see
几乎可以用眼睛完成。我从没见过
you do crossover puzzle because it's
你做交叉填字游戏，因为这很
stupid activity why would I want to do
愚蠢。我为什么要做？
it I think I think you're avoiding it
我觉得你逃避它是
because you're avoiding challenges in
因为你逃避生活中的挑战。
your life you do that in every phase of
你人生的每个阶段都在
your life avoid challenges you always
逃避挑战，你总是
take the easy Road you think that
选择轻松的路。你以为
marrying you was the easy Road are you
嫁给你就是轻松的路吗？你在
kidding okay so that's kind of what it
开玩笑吗？好吧，看起来就是这样。
like I've seen that before have
我以前见过这种情况，你呢？我们也见过。那么
you so have we what's the opposite then
反过来呢？
using the cross word example again if
再用填字游戏的例子，如果
you role playay the opposite scenario
你扮演相反的情景。
okay boy some of these Challenger cross
好的，伙计，有些挑战性填字
puzzles are really
游戏真的
hard really yeah oh did you find
很难。真的。哦，你在做的时候有没有发现特别
something really hard in one you're
难的？ 是
doing now yeah it's like you have to
啊，感觉就像你必须
know the names of these dinosaurs I've
知道这些我
never heard of in order to complete the
从未听说过的恐龙的名字才能完成
puzzle oh my God that sounds impossible
拼图，我的天哪，这听起来不可能，
I know yeah it really does yikes yeah
我知道，确实不可能，哎呀，
what are you working on right now that's
你现在在做什么？这
so hard well I you know I'm trying to do
太难了。嗯，你知道，我正在尝试做
these seduko things oh no I'm having a
这些海妖游戏，哦不，我在这方面遇到了
lot of trouble with those oh those are
很多困难，哦，这些
impossible for me oh my God yeah I like
对我来说是不可能的，我的天哪，是啊，我喜欢
that you really love challenges good
你真的很喜欢挑战，祝你
luck with that I don't think I'll be
好运，我想我
able to help you okay all right okay so
帮不了你。好吧，好吧，好吧，
it kind of looks like that and what what
看起来有点像那样，那么，
are the like fundamental differences
根本区别是什么？
like CU is something being deposited in
比如，CU（你）是在
that first example that's going to be
第一个例子中沉积的东西吗？这将是
Insidious and and to result in the
阴险的，会导致
relationship falling down think of the
关系破裂。想想“
word stupid I used it three times put
愚蠢”这个词，我用了三次，
down criticism
贬低、批评、
contemptuous how does he respond
蔑视。他是如何回应的？
counterattacks you're not smart enough
反击，你不够聪明，
to do these defensiveness these are like
做不到这些？防御，这些就像是
personality attacks straight from the J
人格攻击，直接来自J（指J，可能是指某种人格攻击或贬低者）。这
exactly exactly and how does that lead
怎么会导致
to divorce how does it feel when
离婚？当
somebody looks down on us is disgusted
有人瞧不起我们，厌恶我们时，我们是什么感觉？
by us does think we're stupid do we want
觉得我们很蠢吗？我们想
to be close to that person M do we want
和那个人亲近吗？我们想
to have sex with that person mm do we
和那个人发生性关系吗？我们
trust that person no we do not we pull
信任那个人吗？不，我们不信任，我们会
away from them it can be much more
疏远他们。这种不满可能
subtle as well than you demonstrated
比你刚才展示的要微妙得多，比如，
that contentment can show up in a in a
这种不满在对话中会以哪些最微妙的方式表现出来？比如，你
conversation so you wouldn't you know I
知道，
I've asked you to do the dishes you
我让你洗碗，你不会真的
wouldn't really think of getting your
想把手
hands wet to do the dishes would you so
弄湿去洗碗吧？
that's I really hate getting my hands
我真的很讨厌把手
wet okay so that was a little bit of
弄湿，好吧，我刚才有点讽刺，确实有点讽刺。
sarcastic it was sarcastic but getting
但是把手
your hands wet I mean it's it's
弄湿，我的意思是，这就像是一种
like it's contempt again what would what
轻蔑。
advice would you give to me then I'm 31
你会给我什么建议？我31
years old I'm four years into my
岁，
relationship you're what 36 years into
恋爱四年了，你结婚36年了，
your marriage 37 37 years into your
37年了。
marriage what advice would you give to
你会给我什么建议，才能
me to make sure that I get 37 years deep
确保我的婚姻也能像你一样长久？
you know you've given me lots of advice
你知道，你今天给了我很多
today about how to argue and how to
关于如何争吵和如何
resolve conflict get this get this
解决冲突的建议。拿好这个
notebook I'm going to get a notebook I'm
笔记本，我要走了。 我打算买个笔记本，随身带着，一旦
notebook and the minute we have an
我们吵架，
argument I'm going to start taking notes
我就开始记笔记。
yeah that's my solution you know and do
嗯，这就是我的解决办法。你知道吗？你
you do you know her dreams this is a
知道她的梦想吗？这
really good question CU I think I know
真是个好问题。CU，我想我知道
her dreams but I've never really asked
她的梦想，但我从来没有
directly oh which I probably should have
直接问过。哦，也许我应该问问的，从
according to Julie's eyes yeah you might
朱莉的眼神来看。嗯，你可能
be surprised by the answer yes sir and
会对答案感到惊讶。是的，先生。
does she know yours and why they're so
她知道你的梦想吗？以及为什么它们对
important to you beyond just yeah it's
你如此重要？嗯，这很
fascinating I'm not even sure I know
有意思。我甚至不确定自己是否了解
mine which is a bit of an issue wonder
我的梦想，这有点问题。我想知道
how does it relate to you being from
这和你来自布瓦纳有什么关系？
bwana yeah it's it's an interesting
嗯，这很有趣，
thing because I think some sometimes
因为我认为有时
we're scared of voicing our dreams
我们害怕说出自己的梦想，
because we think it might result in
因为我们担心这可能会让我们
figuring out that they're unaligned like
发现它们并不一致。比如，
I think if I asked her what her dreams
我想如果我问她她的梦想是什么，她会说
were she's she's very ambitious she
她很有抱负，她
wants to start a family think she wants
想组建家庭，她想
to live in the the sun somewhere my
住在阳光明媚的地方。我的
dreams are probably more focused on I
梦想可能更集中在“我
want to start a family 2 but I want to I
想组建家庭”上。但是我想……我
love doing this podcast there's only a
爱 做这个播客，
couple of cities in the world where I
世界上只有几个城市
can do it um and there's only one city
适合我，嗯，而且
in the world where I think I can do this
我觉得世界上只有一个城市适合我做这个
podcast and it's sunny and that's here
播客，而且阳光明媚，那就是这里。
oh and she might not like being here but
哦，她可能不喜欢待在这里，
for a variety of reasons so it's like
原因有很多。所以，
and then you when you have kids you
当你有了孩子，你就会
realize that you can't just fly around
意识到你不能
like I do now I have we have to be
像我现在这样到处飞来飞去。我们必须
together and present and raise the kids
在一起，陪伴孩子，一起抚养他们。
so I don't know in my head I've just
所以，我不知道，我心里
thought cross that bridge when we come
想的是，到时候再说吧。这算不算一种
to it is that a good way to deal with
好的
life
生活方式？嗯，
no well it's not a bad way it's not a
这不算坏，这不算
bad way you know it it depends on uh
坏。你知道，这取决于
your timing uh but the book we wrote
你的时机。我们写了一本书，叫《
eight dates uh which gives you
八次约会》，这本书里有一些非常
really important as you are establishing
重要的对话，尤其是在你建立
a long-term relationship or if you're
长期关系的时候，或者如果你
already in one but you haven't had
已经有了一段关系，但
conversations like these in a while then
很久没有进行过类似的对话，那么
those are great to have and you don't
这些对话就很有意义。你不必
have to be afraid you know that your
害怕，要知道你们的
dreams
梦想可能截然不同，
because if there's a lot of love of you
因为…… 你
know with maybe a couple of exceptions
知道，爱是存在的，除了少数例外，
out there you can figure out a way to
你总能找到办法维系这段关系。
make it work what advice would you give
你会给我什么建议呢？
to me then I want all of the advice that
我想听听你
you haven't yet given me today okay so
今天还没给我的所有建议。好的，其中
one of them would be just remember that
一条建议是，记住
85% turning towards figure okay turn
85%的时间里要主动靠近对方。
towards her as much as you can you don't
尽可能多地靠近她，我指的不是身体上的靠近，而是
mean physically you mean no yeah I mean
身体上的靠近。
if she makes a little bit for
如果她主动和你建立
connection like Hey Stephen um come into
联系，比如“嘿，斯蒂芬，来
the kitchen I want to show you something
厨房，我想给你看点东西”，你就
get up and go to the kitchen 85% of the
起身去厨房。至少85%的
time at least try do your best it's not
时间里要努力尝试，尽力而为。这不可能
going to be perfect it's 86% by the way
完美，86%的时间里，
oh honey see here's my numbers man I can
亲爱的，你看，这是我的数据。我
always count on him to come up with the
总是可以指望他想出办法。好的，
Stephen okay 86% of the time yeah so
斯蒂芬，你得更加努力。86%的时间里，好的，这
that's a good one another one is when
很好。另一条建议是，当
and you are talking about an
你在谈论某个
issue work really hard to not blame and
问题时，要努力做到不责备、
not criticize yep describe
不批评。描述
yourself your own
你自己的
feelings what situation you're upset
感受，你对什么情况感到不满，
about and what your positive need is not
以及你积极的需求是什么，而不是消极的需求。
the negative one anything else John we
约翰，我们
have this great card deck called
有一副很棒的卡片，叫做“
expressing your needs I don't know if if
表达你的需求”。我不知道
you got a copy of that one no no you can
你有没有，没有，你可以
download it on the on the App Store
从App Store下载，叫
gotman cardex have it on your phone and
Gotman Cardex，把它放在你的手机里。
once a week just sit down with her and
每周一次，和她坐下来，一起看看卡片，然后
go through and say okay here's here's
说：“好，这是我
two things I need this week why why
这周需要的两件事，为什么
should I do that because then it's real
我应该这样做？”这样她就能很
clear you know and she can tell you what
清楚地告诉你，她也能告诉你
happy this week and you know rather than
这周你可以做哪两件事让她开心。你知道，与其听天由命，不如……
leaving it a chance you know you're a
你知道你是个
man that loves maths right yes give me
热爱数学的人，对吧？是的，跟我说说
mathematical conclusions you've been
你在“
through the love lab I think the most
爱情实验室”的工作中得出的最有趣的数学结论吧。我觉得最
amazing one is
神奇的结论是：
that the only way to be powerful in a
在一段关系中，获得力量的唯一途径
relationship is to accept
是接受
influence and it's so
影响。这听起来很
counterintuitive but that turns out to
违反直觉，但事实证明它非常
be really powerful that I I found that
有效，这让我很
very surprising the only way to be
惊讶。获得力量的唯一途径
powerful is basically to be
基本上就是变得容易受
influenceable be flexible be movable
影响、灵活变通、
listen to your partner and try to accept
倾听你的伴侣，并尝试接受
some influence from what they're
他们话语中的一些影响，当然，
saying not perfectly of course anything
不可能完全做到。还有，
else say what you need don't expect your
说出你的需求，不要…… 别指望你的
partner to read your mind because they
伴侣能读懂你的心思，因为他们
never
永远也
can anything else yep one more this is
做不到。对了，还有一个问题，这是
one of our favorite
我们最喜欢的
questions ask your partner once a
问题之一：每周问你的伴侣一次，
week what is something can do next week
下周可以做些什么
to make you feel more loved we have this
让你感觉更被爱。我们
annual honeymoon that we do uh that
每年都会进行一次蜜月旅行，已经坚持了
we've done for 23 years and we go away
23年。我们会去远方，
and bring our kayak and we ask each
带上我们的皮划艇，在
other three questions over two weeks
两周的时间里互相问三个问题：
what sucked about this year what did you
今年最糟糕的事情是什么？今年你
like about this year and what do you
喜欢什么？你
want next year to be like so we have
希望明年是什么样子？我们每年都会抽出时间来认真
take a hard look at our lives and see
审视我们的生活，看看
what needs to change here's the deal
需要做出哪些改变。
yeah because we work together and we're
其实，我们一直都在交流，因为我们一起工作，我们一直在
expressing love and affection and
表达对彼此的爱、关怀和
gratitude to one another all the time
感激之情，
and a lot of our work is
而且我们的很多工作都很
fun it would be great if we went out on
有趣。如果我们能
more
多
dates the pandemic kind of interfered
约会就好了。疫情在很大程度上干扰了
with that quite a
这一点。
bit um but we loved it but we loved it
但是我们很喜欢约会，我们喜欢约会，
and we love going on dates it's just
只是
we're so darn busy like everybody else
我们和其他人一样，真的太忙了。
right and we're really old Stephen so
而且我们年纪也不小了，斯蒂芬，所以
we're getting
我们……
tired John what does Julie mean to you
约翰，你累了吗？朱莉对你来说意味着什么？
what does she mean to me what a question
她对我来说又意味着什么？真是个好问题。
W she's
她
really the most important thing in my
真的是我生命中最重要的人，
life absolutely the most important thing
绝对是最重要的。
waking up in the morning and having her
每天早上醒来，她就在
be next to me is such a joy and cuddling
我身边，这感觉太棒了。
with her and our dog is just wonderful
和她还有我们的狗狗依偎在一起，
thing every morning and and now we get
每天早上都无比美好。现在我们
to be grandparents together we have this
一起当爷爷奶奶了，我们有一个
two-year-old little boy that we're both
两岁的小男孩，我们都
in love with and we get to see our
爱他。我们还能见证
daughter be a mom you know
女儿成为母亲。你知道吗？
anybody's ever given me is to become a
成为父亲是我收到的最棒的礼物。
father she means everything to me she
她对我来说意义非凡。如果她
wasn't in your life what would you be
不在你的生命中，你会错过什么？一切的一切。
Everything Julie what does John mean to
朱莉，约翰对你来说意味着什么？
you he's the most adorable wonderful
他​​是
person I've ever had in my life what he
我生命中最可爱、最棒、最讨人喜欢的人。他对
means to me is that he has healed me
我来说意味着他治愈了我过去
from a lot of my own past
很多创伤。
trauma he makes me laugh all the time
他总是逗我笑，
and I didn't know how to laugh at all I
而我以前根本不会笑，
never laughed before I met
遇见他之前我从未笑过。
him he supports my
他支持我的
dreams nobody ever cared about my dreams
梦想，
knew about my dreams before I met him
遇见他之前没有人关心我的梦想，也没有人知道我的梦想。
including crazy dreams like going to
包括像独自去南极这样的疯狂梦想，
Antarctica by myself he supported that
他都支持，这难道
isn't that
不令人
amazing he is the most supportive
惊叹吗？他是最支持我、
wonderful man and the other thing is
最棒的男人。还有一点就是
that he's so damn smart I knew I would
他非常聪明，我知道我永远不会感到
never be bored and he reads a million
无聊。他的阅读量是我的百万
times as much as I do I mean I read a
倍，我的意思是，我读
lot but he reads so much that I'm
很多书，但他读得更多，所以我不断
constantly learning from him
地从他身上学习。
so he's a source of knowledge source of
他是知识的源泉，是
laughter source of sunshine source of a
欢笑的源泉，是阳光的源泉，是一个非常棒的
fabulous fabulous fabulous daughter and
女儿、
son-in-law and grandson and he's got the
女婿和孙子的源泉。他拥有
world that's what he means to me besides
世界上最美丽的眼睛，这就是他对我来说的意义。除此之外，
that I love his hat he always wears the
我喜欢他的帽子，他总是戴着
same hat and he has for like 40 years
同一顶帽子，已经戴了40年了，
because it makes him look like a Jewish
因为这让他看起来像个犹太
intellectual B bik what could be better
知识分子。还有什么比这更好呢？
she's talking about my leather hat oh
她说的是我的皮帽。哦，好吧，
come out I think February 1st M January
我要说的是《鱼人》这本书，它应该会在2月1日或1月
30th yeah ah okay why did you write this
30日出版。啊，好吧，你为什么要写这
book why was it so important there's so
本书？为什么它如此重要？
many things that you could have written
你有很多研究成果可以写。
about from one of your research but for
但
some reason you wrote a book called
不知为何，你写了一本叫《正确
fight right why did why take a look at
战斗》的书，为什么？看看
the
世界，
especially in the United States has
尤其是在美国，战斗比以往任何时候都
become more polarized than
更加两极分化；
ever secondly hatred has become
其次，仇恨竟然被
sanctioned as uh a fine way to express
允许成为表达政治观点的绝佳方式。人们之间
there been any listening to each other
有谁倾听过彼此的声音吗？一个也
zip none and so you know we can't we're
没有。所以你 我知道我们做不到，我们
not politicians we're not going to w the
不是政客，我们不可能改变
whole social system but if we can change
整个社会体系，但如果我们能改变
how people listen to one another and
人们在家中彼此倾听和
love one another at home which is what
相爱的方式——这是
we know the most about then we can hope
我们最了解的——那么我们就可以祈祷
and pray for a ripple effect to move out
并希望这种影响能扩散
into
到
society and create more love out in the
社会各个层面，在世界这个我们如此需要爱的地方创造更多的爱。
Making Peace one family at a time oh I
一次一个家庭地缔造和平，哦，我
love it nice
喜欢这个说法，不错。
one we have a closing tradition on this
我们这个播客有个结束的传统，上一位
podcast where the last guest leaves a
嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个
question for the next guest not knowing
问题，但下一位嘉宾并不知道问题会
who they're leaving it for I'm going to
留给谁。我要
ask you both to answer the question I
请你们两位回答这个问题，我得
don't get to see it until I open the
打开书才能看到。好了，开始吧。
go oh interesting so I'm going to start
哦，有意思。那我先请
this with Julie um if you could go back
朱莉回答。嗯，如果你能回到过去，
and tell your parents any one thing at
在你出生的时候对你的父母说一句话，你会说
the time you were born what would it be
什么？
I would tell my
我会告诉我的
father would you please stay
父亲：“请你每周至少在家待一天，而不是
abandoning my mother every single day
每天、每周七天都抛弃​​我的母亲。”
seven days a week I would tell my
我会告诉我的
mother stop being critical stop being
母亲：“不要总是批评，不要总是轻蔑，
contemptuous try to look for what all of
试着去发现
us are doing
我们所有人做得好的地方，然后
right and say that rather than only
说出来。” 与其只
pointing out what we're doing wrong why
指出我们做错了什么，不如问问他为什么
wasn't
不……
he he was a
他是个
cardiologist so he was constantly gone
心脏病专家，所以他总是忙着救人，
basically uh as a cardiologist and when
基本上就是个心脏病专家。
he wasn't he was playing golf classic
不救人的时候，他就去打高尔夫，典型的
cardiologist and I think my mother may
心脏病专家。我觉得我妈可能把
have drove him a little
他
crazy cuz she was a very very disturbed
逼疯了，因为她是个精神非常不稳定的
individual so he
人，所以他
escaped and he was a 50s 1950s father
逃走了。他是个典型的五十年代父亲，对吧？
right which meant all he had to do was
这意味着他只需要养家糊口就行了，对吧？不用管
children and your mother I'm guessing
孩子。我猜你妈
didn't know how to fight in the way that
不知道怎么像
you describe it in this book oh my God
你在书里描述的那样反抗。我的天哪，
no no no no no no no my my mother had
不不不不不不不不。我妈亲眼
witnessed horrible violence and rape
目睹过家里的可怕暴力和强奸，
within her home she was incested herself
她自己小时候也被乱伦，
child she didn't feel like she had any
她觉得自己除了
value other than her beauty and she was
美貌之外没有任何价值，而她确实
very very beautiful
非常非常漂亮，
so she didn't feel entitled to ask for
所以她觉得自己没有权利要求
what she needed and you need to feel at
自己需要的东西。你至少需要有这种感觉，
least some of that in order to fight for
才能争取
what you want and what you need and J
你想要的和需要的。我也有
same question yeah what would I tell my
同样的问题。是啊，我该怎么跟
parents yeah I I think
父母说？嗯，我想
that I would tell my
我…… 首先，我会告诉我的
parents first of all how much I love and
父母我有多爱他们，多
appreciate them for who they were and I
感激他们，感谢他们本来的样子。我
don't think I did that
觉得我做得还不够，
enough um especially with my dad and I
尤其是对我的父亲。我
would also tell my parents to be better
还会告诉我的父母，要
parents toward my
对我的
sister cuz we really lived in two
妹妹好一点，因为我们真的生活在两个
different
不同的
families and my sister didn't have an
家庭里。我的妹妹
temperament and um and she was extremely
性格比较难相处，而且她在
talented musically and I wish they had
音乐方面非常有天赋。我希望他们能
supported her music and loved her better
支持她的音乐，更爱她一些，
because she really needed it
因为她真的需要这些。
and I think they could have done a much
我觉得他们本可以做得更好，
better job being parents of her they did
他们把我教育得
a great job with me what was the cost to
很好。但
your
你
sister I think she felt really
妹妹为此付出了什么代价呢？我觉得她
unloved still
仍然感觉自己不被爱，
especially by my
尤其是不被我的
mom and I felt very loved by my
母亲爱。而我则感受到母亲深深的爱。
mom I think that's kind of served to
我觉得这在某种程度上
make sense of why you both do what you
解释了你们俩为什么会做现在做的事。
you do in many respects you both have an
在很多方面，你们都有各自的
origin story which is sort of pertinent
成长经历，这在
and present in the work that you do and
你们的作品中都扮演着重要的角色。
the perspectives you both take on the
你们对
subject matter of love and relationships
爱和人际关系的看法
comes from two very different places and
来自两个截然不同的地方。
um we all have an origin story of love
我们每个人都有关于爱
and relationships and I think think we
和人际关系的成长经历，我觉得我们
often discount how important and
常常低估了
formative that is for us I mean I know
它对我们的重要性和塑造作用。我知道
from myself personally my my life is
就我个人而言，我的生活
dominated by by love and relationships
被爱和人际关系所主导。
and My Success my business everything
我的成功、我的事业，
that I've done in my life is comes back
我人生中所做的一切，都源于
to the early relationships I had my
早期的人际关系。我对
perspective on love and the lack of Love
爱的看法，以及对爱的缺失，
or you know the love that I once needed
或者说我曾经渴望的爱，都源于此。
so thank you so much to both of you for
非常感谢你们两位，
really being seen as the you know you
你们被
are seen as the Pioneers on this subject
视为这个领域的先驱。在
recording that so many of my guests have
录制节目之前，我就告诉过你们，我的很多嘉宾都曾
come on this show and mentioned your
上过这个节目，提到过你们的
work they've quoted your work and these
工作，引用过你们的研究成果。他们当中
are some of the most successful people
不乏世界上最成功的人士，
in the world they're scientists they're
他们是科学家、
neuroscientists Etc but even long before
神经科学家等等。甚至在
I got to meet you many years ago I did a
我认识你们之前很多年，我曾在
live show across the UK and I was
英国各地进行过一场现场演出，当时我在
love lab and on stage in front of
舞台上，在成千上万的观众面前，引用了你们“爱实验室”的研究成果。
people so thank you for turning the
所以，感谢你们让大家
lights on to a subject that matters so
关注到这个
much to human happiness and health as
对人类幸福和健康至关重要的话题，
we've discovered because it's some of
因为正如我们所发现的，这是
the most important work that I think
我认为
anyone could do in for Humanity and you
任何人都能为人类做的最重要的工作之一，而你们一直
guys have been leading the way in doing
走在前列。非常
it so thank you both so much thank you
感谢！ 非常感谢你们两位，
stepen for having us on your podcast
Stepen，谢谢你们邀请我们参加你的播客节目。
thank you so much given that you have
鉴于你
interviewed some of the most successful
采访过地球上一些最成功、最
brilliant people on the
杰出的人，能以这种
planet uh to be honoring love in the way
方式来颂扬爱情，真的非常难得。
that you're doing because by doing that
因为你这样做，
you are really endorsing how important
实际上是在强调
love is and everybody needs to hear that
爱情的重要性，而每个人都需要听到这一点。
so thank you well said honey
所以，谢谢你，说得真好，亲爱的。
indeedy everyone needs to go get your
确实，每个人都应该去读读你的
books I mean there's quite a lot of them
书。我的意思是，你的书有很多，
but this particular one here I think
但我认为这本是
everyone should start with because
每个人都应该从读的第一本。因为
conflict resolution knowing how to um
冲突解决之道，也就是如何
take on conflict knowing how to address
应对冲突，如何处理冲突，
it knowing how to be a better sparring
如何成为
partner in relationships so that it can
关系中更好的伙伴，这样才能让
be you and your partner versus the
你们一起面对
problem versus instead of you versus
问题，而不是你们彼此对抗。
your partner I think is foundational to
我认为这对于
us finding the love that most of us are
我们找到大多数人都在
searching for but that feels so elusive
寻找却又难以捉摸的爱情至关重要。
so I'd recommend everybody to go get the
所以我推荐大家去读读这
book I'm going to link in the
本书，我会在
description below thank you so much
下面的描述里放上链接。非常感谢，
we're
我们
done
结束了。
[Music]
[音乐]
oh
哦